[MUSIC]
[音乐]
Stanford University.
斯坦福大学
>> Okay, well,
welcome to lecture number 14 of Stanford CS193p.
欢迎来到斯坦福大学 CS193P 第14课。
It's winter of 2015 and today we're gonna talk
2015冬季学期，今天我们要讨论手机
about how your phone can find out where it is,
定位的问题，
where it is in the world or where it is on the planet.
手机如何得知在这个星球上的位置。
And there's really two parts to that: Core Location which
这个技术由两部分组成：CoreLocation框架和
is one framework and
then MapKit which is another framework.
MapKit框架。
And so Core Location is the kind of the guts of it,
CoreLocation是这个技术的底层，是一个没有UI部分
the non-UI underlying part of it and then MapKit is the user
的框架，而MapKit是UI层面的框架，
interface, how we're gonna present.
用于把地图上的信息
This information about where we are on a map to the user.
展现给用户。
And so I'm gonna try and blast through these slides as
我会尽快讲完课件，之后我们会一起
quickly as I can so I can get to a demo.
做一个demo。
Because you learn a lot from the demo, I think,
我觉得你们会从demo学到更多的东西，
seeing it in practice.
从实际操作中学到更多。
And in my demo, I'm gonna show a map, obviously, and
在这个demo里，我们要展示一个地图，然后
then I'm gonna put some waypoints on it, and we'll
在地图上放置一些路径点，然后我们会学到如何从地图界面
learn how we can segue from a map to show more information.
跳转出去以看到更多的信息。
And then if I have time, we will show how to do overlays,
如果还有时间的话，我们会做一些覆盖层，
which is something that sits on top of the map, and
实际上就是一些覆盖在地图上面的图层，当地图
as the map zooms in and moves around,
缩放或者移动的时候，
the overlay stays with it.
覆盖层会跟着一起动。
So it might be your route through traffic, or
比如沿着交通道路的路线，在我们的demo里
in our case we're going to have a vacation, and
我们会计划我们的假期，
we're gonna say where we went on our vacation.
制定假期要去的地方。
All right?
All right, so let's talk about Core Location,
好，下边我们来讲CoreLocation。
this underlying part.
底层的部分。
It's just a framework for managing your location and
这是一个管理你位置和方向
your heading, okay?
的框架。
What direction you're pointing and where you are.
你朝着哪个方向以及你在哪。
And it has no user interface in Core Location, okay?
在CoreLocation里并没有UI的部分。
This is all purely managing the location themselves.
只是单纯的管理位置的信息而已。
And the basic object that represents a location is
用于代表位置的基本对象叫做
called the CLLocation, right?
CLLocation。
CL for Core Location.
CL就是CoreLocation的意思。
And then location because it's the location.
叫location因为它代表一个位置。
And it has the properties you would imagine.
它有你能想象到的所有属性，比如
Coordinate, altitude, horizontal and
关于这个位置的坐标，高度，
vertical accuracy of the measurement of this location.
水平或者垂直的精度，
Time stamp, speed.
时间戳，速度
Course, where you're headed.
当然，还有你的方向。
Those kind of things.
所有的这些东西。
And the main thing about the location, of course,
当然对于位置来说最重要的
is a latitude and longitude.
属性就是经纬度。
And it gives you a latitude and longitude.
它会给你一个经纬度信息。
But you notice,
但是要注意，
I say, where, approximately, is this location?
这只是一个近似的信息。
Because.
No location object is necessarily gonna be
因为目前并没有定位的设备可以告诉你现在
right exactly where you are because we don't have any
所处的准确位置，所以
location measuring
hardware that can tell you exactly where you are.
位置的对象不会是完全准确的。
I mean GPS is pretty darn good, very close.
我的意思是说GPS非常好，已经很接近正确的位置了。
But there are other ways which we're gonna talk about,
但是我们要讨论的是另外的方式，
about measuring where you are that are much less accurate.
用一个相对低的精确度去计算位置。
So a CLLocationCoordinate2D.
这个属性CLLocationCoordinate2D，
2-D meaning it's on the ground,
2D意思是在地上的位置，
not including your altitude.
不包括高度。
Is an approximate latitude and longitude.
是一个近似的经纬度。
And we'll talk a little bit about that accuracy and
之后我们会说一点关于精确度以及
how we know what it is.
如果获取精确度的问题。
And then your altitude is a separate variable, altitude.
高度是另外一个变量，altitude。
And so the accuracy
精确度
is measured in both horizontal and vertical space, right, for
是用来同时衡量水平和垂直空间的，
altitude and for your horizontal position.
也就是水平的位置以及垂直的高度。
And, it's not like your accuracy is a percent
精确度并不是一个百分比的数值或者类似
accuracy, or something like that.
的东西。
It's really just one of these key pre-defined terms up here.
它实际上是一组预定义好的信息。
So, the most accurate is called best for navigation,
最高的精度叫做 BestForNavigation。
and that's certainly gonna use GPS to find that, and
这个精度肯定需要使用GPS，它的意思是
that's the kind of thing where you're driving in your car,
当你开车用导航的时候，你肯定
and you don't wanna miss a turn.
不希望错过转弯的路口。
So that's. Really accurate location
所以，需要非常高的精度
finding.
To get this,
去达到这个目的。
you're gonna wanna have your phone plugged in, okay?
在这个精度，你需要让你的手机保持充电状态。
Because more accuracy takes more power.
因为精度越高越费电。
Talk about that in a second.
一会儿会详细说这个。
Then there's just best,
这个最高的精度
which is kind of probably gonna use GPS.
要用到GPS，
And then there's nearest ten meters.
这个10米附近的精度。
Probably a mix, of maybe GPS and WiFi.
可能是GPS和wifi混用的，
Then there is hundred meters is probably mostly
这个百米附近的精度可能只用到
gonna be using WiFi.
wifi。
Then there's kilometers and three kilometers, that's gonna
一公里以内和三公里以内的精度，会用到
be using cell towers to find out where you are.
基站来确定你的位置。
Okay? This is kind of the groups or
明白了吗？精度实际上是一个
the categories of accuracy.
预定义好的组。
More accuracy means more power.
更高的精度就更费电。
Because the communication with cell towers is pretty low.
跟基站通讯耗电非常低，
Your phone's doing it all the time anyway.
手机会一直跟基站通讯。
And so it's a pretty low power activity.
这是一个耗电很低的活动。
WiFi is pretty good.
wifi就有点费电了，
It's got a big database of all the WiFi nodes or
全世界所有的wifi节点以及wifi区域
many of the WiFi zones in the world.
是一个非常大的数据库。
And so if it sees you close to some of them,
如果你靠近它们，
it can triangulate your location pretty accurately.
它们可以通过三角定位以一个很高的精度确定你的位置。
Like at a place like Stanford where there's
比如在斯坦福大学这个有无数个wifi
just billions of WiFi nodes everywhere.
节点的地方。
It's pretty darn accurate, and kind of pretty low power,
地位会非常准确而且不是很耗电，
not super low power.
但也不是最省电的。
And then there's GPS.
最后是GPS，
Obviously super accurate.
这个是最精确的。
It doesn't work everywhere.
但不是在哪都能用。
If you're underground or in a well-shielded building,
如果你在地下或者在屏蔽非常好的建筑物里，
you're not gonna get GPS, of course.
GPS就不能用了。
But where it does work,
但是在能用的时候，
it's very accurate, but it uses a lot of power.
定位会非常精确，同时也会非常费电。
Okay, it's gonna drain your battery.
电池很快就会被耗干。
And when you talk about any kind of location app,
当我们谈到关于位置的app时，
you're talking about the battery, okay?
实际上我们在谈的是电池。
Because if your app does a lot of location stuff and
如果你的app做了跟多定位的事儿，但是你没仔细的
you're not careful with it,
设计的话，
people are gonna run your app for a few weeks and
用户很可能在用了你的app几周以后说：
they're gonna say, oh, I had to delete that app.
”哦，我得删了这个app，电池用的
My battery would just run down right away.
太快了。“
Okay?
So you have to be careful with doing location
所以做定位功能的时候要特别小心，
vis-a-vis power.
能耗的问题。
And we'll talk a little bit about that down the road here.
我们一会儿会再讲一些这个问题。
So speed, the speed is your instantaneous speed.
下面说速度，速度指的是你的瞬时速度。
It's not like your average
并不是在一段时间内
speed over the last however long.
你的平均速度。
It's like you know,
it's between last measurements it's telling you your speed.
大意就是在两次取值之间的速度。
So it's kind of good for driving,
在开车的时候会
like you're driving around, it wouldn't be that great for
非常有用，但是在走路的时候就
walking around, that kind of thing.
不是那么有意义了。
Course is just going to be.
course代表方向，
It's probably.
I think you can use some magnetometers, so
这可能是磁力计的术语，来表示
it's actually kind of an idea of where you're headed.
你面朝哪个方向。
But it's also mostly just looking at your track.
但是可能它更倾向于你运动轨迹的方向。
Right? Measuring your locations and
测量你的位置然后判断
seeing, well, you're generally headed in this direction.
你前进的大致方向。
And then time stamps, obviously,.
下边是时间戳，
Time stamps are more important than you think because
时间戳这个属性比你想象的要重要因为当你
as you ask for
想要得到你的位置
location you're not gonna get location instantaneously.
的时候，这个操作不是瞬间完成的。
Okay, it might take a little delay.
可能会有一些延迟。
You walk under something that blocks you from GPS and
你可能会走到一些东西的下边阻塞了GPS，过一会儿才会开始获取
it comes back, or you walk between WiFi nodes.
位置，或者你穿行于不同的wifi节点，
It picked up one, drops another.
系统识别出一个，又弃掉了另一个。
So these locations can come in not in a nice even stream.
所以获取位置可能不是一个实时的操作。
So you sometimes have to look at the time stamp to see well
你可能需要查看时间戳检查这个位置信息是什么时候获取的，
how old is this location, is this you know, a minute ago?
一分钟以前还是
Or is this just like a second ago?
一秒之前？
So how do you get one of these CLLocation objects?
那么我们如何得到CLLocation对象呢？
You get them from a CLLocationManager, okay?
通过 CLLocationManager。
Now a CLLocationManager kind of like.
CLLocationManager 就好像是，
Core motions manager in a way.
在某种程度上类似CoreMotion manager。
You know, there's really only one GPS in the system.
系统里只有一个GPS，
But we don't usually do the same thing where we share this
但是我们不像CoreMotion那样之用一个
one core motion manager.
manager。
You can have different core location managers.
我们可以用多个 CLLocationManager 。
But there are things you're gonna set on it that are gonna
但是设置它的时候可能会改变
effect a little bit about how the hardware works.
一点硬件的工作方式。
And you'll see how that goes a little bit.
你会看到是怎么改变的。
One thing that's cool about CoreLocationmanager
CLLocationManager 有一个很棒的功能就是它可以
is you can simulate from Xcode.
在Xcode里模拟位置。
If you go down to the bottom bar of Xcode there,
在Xcode下边的状态条这里，
you'll see there's like a little arrow thing.
有一个小箭头。
And if you click on that,
点这个小箭头，
it gives you a menu of GPX entries.
会有一些GPX入口。
GPX, the same kind of GPX that we're doing with tracks.
GPX就是我们在做轨迹的时候的GPX。
Which are just locations on the planet and
是一些地球上的位置，
you pick one and
你选其中的一个
it'll make your phone seem like it's in Mumbai and so
模拟你的手机在孟买，
you can see if your app works when it thinks it's in Mumbai.
所以你可以测试你的app是不是能正确的显示位置在孟买。
So that's kind of a fun part of it.
这个功能挺有趣的。
The CLLocationManager works a lot like the Core motion
CLLocationManager 运作方式非常像 CoreMotionManager。
manager.
You check to see if the hardware exists first
先检查是不是有相应的硬件，
because not all phones have
因为不是所有的手机
all kinds of updating that you would want.
都有定位的硬件。
Then you're gonna create an instance and
然后就想往常一下创建一个实例并且设置
set a delegate, usually, okay.
代理。
Then you configure it to what you want, and
然后你就可以按需求设置它，然后
then it's gonna start sending you delegate messages.
它就开始发送代理信息。
So it's a little different than Core Motion.
有一点和CoreMotion不一样。
You don't use a block-based thing.
没有block。
You have a delegate, and it's gonna be just sending you
它只是通过代理给你发送
delegate messages, saying, hey, here's some locations
代理信息，告诉你：嘿，给你这些从上次通讯到现在
I've gathered since last I talked to you.
的位置信息
And it is gonna send those to you in kind of a steady
它会通过一个稳定的流向你发送信息。
stream.
Now, you want to monitor your location, but
如果你希望监控你的位置，有几种
there's different ways to monitor your location.
不同的方式。
There's, kind of,
首先是
continual updates where, based on a certain accuracy like,
基于一个特定的精确度，提供持续的更新，
I want to know exactly where I am all the time, okay?
我希望一直得到我的精确位置。
It'll be constantly looking at the GPS and
它会持续的通过GPS获取位置
trying to get your location and
并且尽快
sending them to you as fast as you can.
发送给你。
Or you might say, well,
或者你只是希望我在
I wanna know where I am within a kilometer.
一公里之内的大概位置。
I just wanna have the general region I'm in.
只是希望知道我是不是在一个区域里。
Well then, you know, as you switch cell towers or
然后它会切换到基站，
something like that, it might send you an update saying, oh,
并且通知你和之前你所处的
you're a little different place than you were before.
位置不同。
So, you set the accuracy you want and
也就是说，设置好精确度，它
then it'll start giving you updates.
就是持续的更新。
So, that's one way.
这是一种方式。
There's also a really cool way to say, only tell me when
还有一种更酷的方式，只是在我的位置有
a significant change in location happened.
显著的改变时通知我。
And we'll talk about what significant means.
一会儿我们会说这个“显著”是什么意思。
You can also set regions.
你还可以设置区域。
Like, here's a circular area on the planet.
就是地球上的一个圆形。
When I go into this area, or
当我走进这个圆形或者走出
out of this area, send me an update.
的时候，发送给我一个更新。
So, that's kind of cool.
这个是非常酷的。
So, if you had an app that's, like, reminder app, and
如果你有一个类似提醒的app，
it was gonna remind you to pick up the dry cleaning.
它会提醒你取干洗的衣服。
Well, if you drove through the circle where the,
当你开到干洗店附近的区域时，
around the dry cleaner, maybe it would give you an alert.
它就会给你一个提醒。
Oh, don't forget to pick up the dry cleaning, okay?
别忘了取干洗的衣服。
So, you can do that with regions.
你可以通过划定区域来实现这个功能。
And then, you can also monitor your heading.
你也可以监控你的方向。
Maybe just to make sure you're turned the right way if you're
可以用来确定走路的时候
walking or something, I don't know.
是不是拐了正确的弯
Okay, the part where you have to, is that better?
在获取硬件。。。。。现在声音好点了吗？
The part where you have to ask what hardware you have,
在获取硬件信息的时候，
there's a lot of class functions in CLLocationManager
有很多CLLocationManager的类方法要用到。
that you're gonna use.
I'm not gonna go into all of them in detail.
我不会把它们都讲一遍。
But, the various kinds of monitoring you'll wanna do,
这里会有不同的监控方式选择，
like, significant change monitoring, or
比如，显著位置变更监控或者
region monitoring, or just location services in general.
地区监控，或者只是普通的位置服务。
Because the user might be a little paranoid about your
用户可能对于你获取他们的位置信息
getting their location.
不舒服。
And so, they could turn that off.
所以他们可能会关掉这个服务。
So, you have to call this, like thing, like,
你需要调用 locationServicesEnabled来查看
locationServicesEnabled to find out, is it enabled?
位置服务是不是开启了。
All right, can I even do it?
看我是不是允许获取位置。
And, there's also an authorizationStatus, too.
还有这个authorizationStatus方法。
Be careful of the authorizationStatus,
注意它的Restricted选项。
Restricted.
Okay, Restricted basically means Denied but, it's denied
Restricted基本上等同于拒绝，它通过用户不能
in a way where there's nothing the user can do about it.
改变的方式拒绝定位服务。
So, either parental controls or blocking it, or
比如有上级的控制或者阻塞，又比如当你
maybe you're in an enterprise,
在一个企业里，
a company that blocks it, okay, on your phone.
公司屏蔽了位置服务，
So, in that case,
在这种情况下，
you don't want to put up an alert that says,
你不希望弹出一个警告说，
you're blocking me from getting location,
“你不允许我获取位置，请开启服务“
please enable it, because they can't,
因为他们做不到，
there's nothing they can do, that's different than Denied.
他们什么都做不了，这就是跟拒绝服务的区别。
Okay? And that's true,
所以，
not just in location services but in general, watch out for
不只是位置服务，大部分的服务都要注意
the authorization status of Restricted versus Denied.
Restricted 和 Denied的区别。
So, to get the information, you can just ask it, okay?
我们发出请求之后就可以获取信息。
What's my current, to the best of your knowledge,
我目前的位置信息是
information about my location?
什么样的？
So it'll give you a CL location.
它会返回一个CLLocation。
It's like, this is where you are.
表示你所处的位置。
And it'll be time stamped, you can check it,
是带有时间戳的。
things like that.
But, before we can do any of this, get any information out
但是在我们从CLLocationManager获取信息之前，
of the locationManager, we have to get authorization from
我们需要得到系统，实际上是
the system, really from the user to do that.
用户的授权。
And, you can do that in one or two different ways.
你可以通过两种方式获取授权。
One, is you can
第一种是
request authorization to only access the location info
仅在你的app是当前活动的app时候启动
while your application is the active app, that's
定位服务，这就是
requestWhenInUseAuthorization().
requestWhenInUseAuthorization()方法。
Or you can request to be able to access the user location
或者你可以申请在任何时候都获取位置，
at anytime, even if you're running in the background.
即使你的app在后台的时候。
If you're using some of the significant change monitoring
当你使用显著位置变更监控的时候，
that we're gonna talk about in a few slides,
我们后边的幻灯片会讲这个。
then you'll need this kind of authorization.
这时就需要这种授权。
So, this authorization,
使用上边这两种方法
when you request it with one of these methods,
获得授权的操作都是
happens asynchronously.
异步的。
That's because it's probably gonna put up a panel to
因为可能会给用户展示一个界面。
the user saying,
this application wants to look at your device's location.
比如“这个程序想要使用你设备的位置，
Is that okay?
可以吗？”
And so, you're gonna find out about this authorization via
你可以通过一个代理方法查看你的
a delegate method.
权限状态。
And we'll talk about the locationManager's delegate
我们一会儿会具体讨论 CLLocationManager 的代理。
in a moment.
But, you can look up in the documentation,
你可以去官方文档查看
the name of the method.
方法的名字。
It's basically gonna tell you what your authorization status
它会在你权限发生变化的时候
when your authorization status changes.
通知你权限的状态。
Now, until that authorization is granted by the user,
在用户给你授权之前，
your authorizationStatus,
你的授权状态
which is a method we talked about in the previous slide,
就是前边我们看到的那个方法
there, will be in this NotDetermined state.
会返回 NotDetermined 状态。
And if you're in the NotDetermined state,
如果你在这个状态下，
then you won't be able to get
你不允许获取任何关于
any information about the user's location.
用户位置的信息。
Now, for any of this requesting authorization to
要使授权申请生效，你需要
work, you need to add a key, one of these two keys,
在Info.plist文件里加入一个键，在这两个键
to your Info.plist file.
里二选一。
So, just the one of these keys just has to exist.
这两个键必须得有一个。
If neither of them exist,
如果都没有，
then you won't be able to get any locations.
就不能获取位置信息。
So, it just has to exist.
所以，必须得有一个才行。
It doesn't have have certain value.
不需要有一个特定的值，
Just the key has to be there.
只要键在那就行了。
To add a key to your Info.plist, you can just click
要在Info.plist里加一个键，需要点击
on your Info.plist in your navigator and
这个文件，然后
then right-click in an open in the Info.plist and
在打开的文件里右键点击，在弹出的
choose Add Row from the little context menu that appears.
菜单里选“添加行”。
And so obviously,
显然你需要
you want to put the key here that matches up with the kind
添加与你之前通过代码获得的授权
of authorization that you're gonna request in your code.
相匹配的键。
And so, once you've done that and once you have gotten
当你成功向用户申请到
the authorization from user, then you'll be able to, for
权限以后，你可以，比如说，要求
example, ask the locationManager for
CLLocationManager 通过location 提供
the current location using the location property.
目前的位置。
But we usually don't pull like that.
但是实际上我们不这么做。
Just like in current motion.
在CoreMotion里才会这么做。
It's kind of bad programming to pull.
这是一种不太好的方式。
We want it to tell us when it has something interesting.
我们只希望在它得到我们想要的信息的时候通知我们。
So we set the desiredAccuracy with this CLLocationManager
所以我们需要在 CLLocationManager 里设置 desiredAccuracy
property, desiredAccuracy, and you just set it.
属性。
It's one of those things I talked about before,
这个就是我们之前谈到的精确度属性，
kilometer or BestForNavigation or whatever.
BestForNavigation或者在几公里之内等等。
You can also take a distance filter which is,
你还可以设置 distanceFilter，
don't tell me about location changes unless I move more
在我移动了这些距离的时候给我
than a certain amount, okay?
更新位置。
A meter, ten meters, 100 meters, a kilometer, whatever.
一米，10米，100米，1公里什么的。
So, you set those two things up and
设置好这两个属性，然后
then you just say, okay, start updating my location.
你可以让它开始更新我的位置。
And it's gonna start sending you delegate messages
它就会开始发送位置的
with your location.
代理信息。
And the delegate message method looks like this,
代理信息的方法就像这样，
locationManager CLLocationManager,
locationManager CLLocationManager
that's the sender, didUpdateLocations.
这个是发送人，didUpdateLocations。
Now, notice that that's an array of locations.
注意看，返回的是位置的数组。
That's not just a single location.
并不是一个单独的位置。
Hey, your location changed.
在你位置发生改变的时候返回数组，
Why does that happen?
为什么会这样？
Well, the new phone hardware
这是因为最新的
is incredible when it comes to measuring your location.
定位硬件非常先进。
And it can, even when it's off, okay,
在你的手机关闭，或者屏幕不亮，
when the thing powers, the screen powers down, and it's
或者电量不足，
kind of in a low power state, it's essentially sleeping.
实际上也就是在休眠的状态下。
The GPS thing could still be recording your location.
GPS依然可以记录你的位置信息。
So, you go for a hike, put your phone in your pocket.
比如你正在远足，手机在你的口袋里。
You're walking for miles.
你走了挺远的路。
You don't want your phone awake and using battery, okay?
这时候你不希望你的手机一直是激活状态消耗电量，对吧？
You want it to sleep but
你希望它处于休眠状态
you still want to record where you went.
但是依然可以记录你的位置。
Okay, cuz you're, you know, fitness tracking or
就像健身记录什么的。
something like that.
And it can do that.
手机可以做到这一点。
So fitness tracking apps will use that mechanism.
所以健身类的app会用到这个机制。
So, what happens here is,
用这个机制，
the fitness tracking app can basically set itself up.
这个健身app就可以自动的做好配置。
It says okay, well after the person has moved a certain
当用户移动特定的距离或者间隔
amount or a certain amount of time happens,
特定的时间时，
please tell me where they've been.
更新位置。
And you'll get this update and
然后你就可以拿到这些更新，
it'll have a bunch of locations in there.
这就是为什么会有很多位置更新给你。
Right, again, all time stamped, all telling you.
而且都加上了时间戳。
So, these things are building up in the chip, the GPS chip.
这个机制是定制在GPS芯片里的。
And then the chip reports them in mass.
定制好以后芯片就可以批量更新。
It's really a pretty amazing technology for
这确实是个非常赞的技术，既省电还
keeping your battery alive and still being able to record.
可以持续的记录位置信息。
And this is similar kind of stuff for heading.
记录方向也差不多。
You can get reports from the locationManager,
你可以从location manager那得到更新。
tell me what my heading is, it's changing, tell me.
告诉我现在的方向，如果方向改变，再通知我。
Errors can happen, okay?
错误是经常出现的。
And this is a case, you know, you notice in demos,
你会注意到在demo里，我没什么时间写代码去
I don't have time to write code to check errors.
做错误检查。
Sometimes errors are more
很多时候检查错误是
important to check than others.
非常重要的。
With location, it's pretty important to check, because,
尤其是在位置服务里，因为有可能发生这种情况，比如
things can happen, like, you're using the app and
你在使用一个可以报告位置的app。
it's reporting a location.
And then, all of a sudden,
然后，突然用户觉得：
the user says, I don't like this app knowing where I am.
我不希望这个app能知道我在哪。
And he goes and turns it off.
他就关了这个功能。
Okay, it turns off the location authorization.
他在app寻找位置的时候
So, right in the middle,
就取消了这个app的位置权限。
you can get something, ErrorDenied.
你就会得到一个ErrorDenied错误。
Okay, you can get yourself denied.
用户可以自己关掉它。
You can also get HeadingFailures if your
在磁力计被干扰的时候，
magnetometer's being interfered with, obviously.
你也有可能会得到一个HeadingFailures
You can get LocationUnknown，
在什么都找不到的时候，也许会得到
where it just hasn't been able to see anything yet,
一个LocationUnknown错误，
it's trying but it wants to let you know it's trying.
系统在尝试但是它希望你能知道它在尝试。
So after a certain amount of time with it not being able
所以当过了一段时间它没找到的时候，
to get it, it'll send you that.
它会给你发送这个错误信息。
So, you want to pay attention to the errors there.
你们应该警惕这些错误。
All right.
So, when your app is in the background,
继续，当你的app在后台的时候，
you can actually still get updates.
你依然可以得到更新。
This is one of the few times when your
这是为数不多的app可以在后台可以
app gets to do things in the background.
做的事。
You have to turn a capability on, in that capabilities thing
你可以把它打开，就是打开上次说到的
I talked about last time to do this.
那个功能。
And there's a way to basically say,
还有一种方式就是把app从后台
just wake me up in the background and
唤醒然后查看
tell me what's going on.
更新。
But really, there's two good ways, kind of bigger-ranged
实际上有两种更好的得到更新的办法，
ways, to get notified of things happening.
他们的范围更广一些。
And that's the significant thing and the region thing.
这就是“显著”和区域这两个东西。
So, the significant changes one, you just say,
第一个是显著变更的，你只需要告诉系统，
start monitoring significant changes.
开始监控显著的位置变更。
Now, when you say that.
当你这么通知app的时候
Okay? It's going to
它会开始监控
start monitoring it for you forever until you say stop.
如果你不喊停它就不停下来。
And this is gonna work even if your app is not launched,
甚至在app没启动的时候它也在监控。
let alone if it's in the background.
不管它是不是在后台。
Okay? And so when significant
也就是说，当有显著的位置变化
changes occur, your app will be launched in the background.
发生的时候，你的app会在后台启动。
And you'll have a little bit of time to chew on the fact
系统会需要一点时间来启动并获取
that the significant change.
显著的位置变更，
Or if your app is running, but in the background,
或者你的app正运行在后台，
it will still get notified of these signficant changes.
它依然会收集这些变更。
Okay, now the only thing is, you clearly
不过，在你不打算让你的app
want to turn this off if your app is not actually gonna
对这些变更做处理的时候，显然你希望
do anything when these significant changes come in.
关掉这个功能。
But it's a pretty cool system.
但是这确实是个非常酷的系统。
And it's very low power.
而且非常省电。
It's basically only large changes kind of the change
因为基本上只有很大的位置改变导致你切换
where you move to a different cell tower,
了一个基站的时候才会发送消息，
those kind of low power,
我们知道通过基站来定位是
measuring your location things.
非常省电的。
But it can be really a cool thing to wake up every once in
它也可以每隔一段时间唤醒app然后
a while and say, okay, where am I?
报告位置。
If my app is location-based so
如果我的app是基于位置设计的，
I'm gonna check something out, it's quite interesting.
我就可以根据位置进行响应，非常好的系统。
And you get notified by the delegate when these
当位置变更时，Location Manager的代理会
significant changes happen.
给你发送消息。
And if you get launched,
在app启动的时候，
then your didFinishLaunchingWithOptions.
会调用 didFinishLaunchingWithOptions方法。
That little dictionary that we talked about is gonna have
这个方法里有一个字典的参数，这个字典会有
a key in there.
一个键。
That'll tell you UIApplicationLaunchOptionsLoc-
就是 UIApplicationLaunchOptionsLocactionKey，
ationKey, saying you got launched because
这个说明你的app启动时由于一个显著位置
a significant, you know, a location event happened, so
变更导致的，你需要去
you should go check your location,
查看当前的位置然后
go do something right now.
做出响应。
Okay?
Make sense?
明白了吗？
So that's a pretty cool system.
非常酷的系统。
And the very similar one is the region one,
区域也是非常类似的。
like the dry cleaner example I was telling you about.
我们刚才提到过干洗店app的例子。
And you can create regions.
你可以建立一个区域。
Really there's only two, I think there's only two regions
目前系统可用的区域类型应该是
in the system currently.
只有两种。
Circular region,
一种是圆形区域。
which is a circle around some latitude and longitude.
就是一个地图上的圆圈。
And then a beacon region.
然后是灯塔区域。
So a circular region, you define like this right here.
在圆形区域里，你可以这样定义。
We just say the center and the radius, and
定义它的中心和半径，然后定义
you give it an identifier.
一个标识。
Now you want the identifier.
标识是必要的，
Because, again,
因为
this is gonna work when your app's not running, okay?
你需要在你的app没启动或者在后台
Or when your app's in the background.
的时候也能监控区域。
So you're gonna get woken up.
你需要特定的时候唤醒app。
And when it wakes up, it needs to say,
app被唤醒的时候就会通知你，
oh, this is the region that you walked into.
你刚刚走进了你预设的区域。
The significant change is only when
显著位置变化的通知只会在位置变化的
a significant change happen.
时候发送。
But, here, you,
但是在这里。
it's gonna tell you which region you walked in or
系统会通知你走进或走出了
out of.
哪一个区域。
A beacon region is when you are near another iOS device.
灯塔区域指的是你是否靠近另外一台iOS设备。
That is giving off a beacon.
这台设备就是所谓的灯塔。
Now I'm not gonna talk about how you can make your iOS
在这里我不打算讲如何让你的iOS设备实现
device do that.
这一点。
It's pretty cool, requires a little bit of Bluetooth and
这个非常赞，需要一些蓝牙技术，但是有点
stuff like that, so beyond the scope of this course.
超出我们这个课程的范围。
But the way you monitor for whether you've come in
但是判断你是否进入了一个灯塔的范围，用的就是
range of a beacon is using this region monitoring system.
咱们说的这个区域监控系统。
And so, when you go into a region or out of a region,
当你走进或者走出区域的时候，
you get exit or enter or exit region.
相应的代理方法就会被调用。
And when you go into a beacon area, whether it's a beacon
无论是灯塔区域还是圆形区域，
area or a circular region, you'll get this same thing.
都会调用同样的方法。
And you can also get fail, you know, errors, and so
有时候也会失败，会得到错误，要记得在代码里
you wanna make sure you check those as well.
检查错误。
And since these regions that you're monitoring can work
因为在你的app不运行的时候也可以监控
when you're not running, they have names.
区域，所以它们都有名字。
And you can find out all the regions you're currently
你可以在CLLocationManager的monitoredRegions属性里找到
monitoring by calling this CLLocationManager property,
所有你目前正在监控的区域。
monitoredRegions.
Now, that's an NSSet.
这是一个NSSet类型的属性。
We haven't really talked about NSSet.
我们之前没讲过NSSet。
But an NSSet, kind of like an unordered array.
NSSet类似是一种无序的数组。
The items in there are uniqued.
里边的元素都是唯一的。
It's a set, basically, in terms of mathematical sense,
在数学上讲，这是一个集合。
kind of a set.
类似集合的东西。
And so you just look in there and find out what these
你只需要查看这个属性就可以知道你目前正在
regions are that you're currently monitoring.
监控哪些区域。
Okay? And
you can stop monitoring certain regions or
你也可以停止监控某一个区域或者添加更多的
add more regions or whatever.
监控区域。
There is a limit to the number of regions you can monitor.
可以监控区域的数量是有限制的，
It's big, though.
尽管这个数量很大。
Yeah? >> When you have a beacon
提问：可以监控一个正在
can you find our where the beacon is cycling?
移动的灯塔吗？
>> Yeah, so the question is, if I'm in a beacon region,
好，问题是，当我在灯塔区域的时候，
I think, do I have a slide on that?
我想想是不是有个幻灯片讲这个
I'll get to the beacons in a second.
我们一会儿马上就讲灯塔了。
So the region monitoring distance.
监控区域的大小也是有限制的。
This is a gettable var, a read-only var.
这里有一个只读的变量。
It'll tell you what is the biggest area you can monitor,
这个变量告诉你可以监控距离的最大范围，
so you can't really say, tell me when I'm at Stanford, and
所以你不能说，监控我是不是在斯坦福大学里，因为
have this gigantic region.
这个区域太大了。
Okay, there is a limit, and this will tell you what it is.
大小是有限制的，可以通过这个变量知道这个限制。
So the beacons,
下边说灯塔，
they can detect the range from the beacon.
系统可以检测到与灯塔之间的距离。
So it's just kind of what you're asking for.
就跟你刚才问的差不多。
As you move around, you can tell.
你只要一动，系统就会告诉你
Are you kind of intensely close to the beacon or kind of
现在是离灯塔很近还是中等距离还是
a medium or are you kind of far away from the beacon?
离的很远。
And so you just say startRanging this
你需要调用这个方法。
BeaconsInRegion.
startRangingBeaconInRegion.
And you'll get this didRangeBeacons in region.
然后你就会收到didRangeBeacons这个代理方法发送的信息。
And it will tell you whether you're immediate, near, or
这个方法会告诉你距离灯塔是近，中等距离
far to the range.
还是远。
So it's not really telling you like, direction but it's
但是它不会告诉你方向，但是会告诉你
telling you, you know, close, near, far so that's good.
距离，应该够用了。
Like I said being a beacon requires you to do some stuff
我刚才说了，要成为一个灯塔需要用到
in the Core Bluetooth Framework.
Core Bluetooth框架的技术。
We're not going to talk about that.
我们这个课上不会讲。
You'd have to have this globally unique ID for
你必须给你的灯塔一个全局唯一
your beacon.
的ID。
You have to register with Apple basically.
你需要去苹果注册这个ID。
This is your beacon.
这就是你的灯塔。
It's not just something you just turn it on,
不是说打开设备就可以
start sending out a beacon.
当作一个灯塔了。
You kind of have to identify your beacon.
你需要注册你的灯塔。
So that's it for core location.
前边讲的就是Core Location的内容。
That's the underpinnings.
底层的东西。
And now we're gonna talk about the UI side of this,
现在我们讲UI层面的东西，
which is called MapKit.
也就是MapKit。
Okay?
And MapKit, fundamentally, displays a map.
MapKit简单来说，就是展示地图。
Okay?
It's basically a UIView,
它是一个UIView。
MKMapview is a UIView subclass.
MKMapView是UIView的子类。
And it displays a map of wherever you are on Earth.
它会展示你在地球上的位置。
Okay? And it's using this Apple Maps
它用的是苹果地图的技术
technology to display either a satellite image like this or
来显示卫星图片或者街道名，
just streets and roads, or an overlap, like this one is,
路名，或者一个像这样的覆盖层，可以显示卫星图片和街道名字
of satellite image and the names of roads, et cetera.
什么的。
Okay?
Now, on this map it has what are called annotations.
地图上会有一些注释点。
That's what makes a pin on the app.
就是app里的大头针。
This is a very important term to understand, an annotation.
注释点是一个非常重要的概念。
An annotation is a point on the map.
注释点就是地图上的一个点。
Okay?
Now, an annotation is simple.
注释点很简单。
It's just a protocol, and it has three things in it.
只是一个协议而已，需要实现三个属性。
Coordinate, which is the latitude and longitude, so
第一个是坐标，也就是经纬度，
that CLLocationCoordinate2D thing we saw earlier, and
也就是我们之前看到的CLLocationCoordinate2D类型，然后
then title and subtitle.
就是标题和副标题。
So, here this one you're seeing here,
现在你看见的这个注释点，
the title is Venice, Italy, and it has no subtitle.
标题是“意大利，威尼斯”，没有副标题。
The subtitle would appear as a little smaller
副标题就是在标题下边小一点的字，
text underneath, so it has no subtitle there.
在这里没有副标题。
Okay?
Now you have these annotations,
现在你有了这些注释点，
you need to display them.
你需要把它们显示在地图上。
Now they're displayed with MKAnnotationView subclasses.
它们是通过MKAnnotationView的子类来显示的。
Okay?
Make sense?
明白吗？
MKAnnotations being displayed with MKAnnotationViews.
MKAnnotations需要通过 MKAnnotationViews显示。
And MKPinAnnotationView, which is what you see here,
MKPinAnnotationView，就像你刚才看见的那样，像
looks like a pin.
个大头针。
Now you can write your own MKAnnotationView subclasses
你可以自己写MKAnnotationView的子类，这样就可以在某个位置
and draw whatever you want at that location.
上画任何你想要的效果。
But most times people are using the MKPinAnnotationView
但是大多数的时候人们都会用MKPinAnnotationView，因为
so it's showing up as pins.
它长的像大头针。
Now when you click on the pin, another view comes up,
当你点大头针的时候，另外一个视图就会跳出来，
this white view right here called the pin's callout.
这个白色的视图叫做大头针的标注。
Okay, now don't get confused between the MKAnnotationView
不要把它跟大头针也就是MKAnnotationView
which is the pin.
弄混了。
That's what the MKAnnotationView,
这个是MKAnnotationView，
it draws a pin.
它在地图上绘制一个大头针。
This is a different thing called a callout.
标注是完全不同的东西。
People get confused between the two because there's
大家经常把这两个东西搞混，因为不能直接访问这个
really no pointer to that callout view, you don't,
标注视图，
you know, interact with that callout view directly.
我们不能直接与标注视图进行交互。
Instead what you're able to do is set the left and
但是我们可以设置左右两个
right accessory views.
辅助视图。
So here we got a left accessory view,
这里是一个左辅助视图。
which is a little image, and
是一个小图片，右辅助视图是一个
the right accessory view is a little button.
小按钮。
You can set those.
你可以设置它们。
But you don't interact with the view.
但是你不能与这个视图交互。
So, but that's a callout view, and
这个标注视图只会在
it only shows when you click on the pin.
你点大头针的时候才会弹出来。
If you click on the pin, it shows the callout view.
如果你点击大头针，标注视图就出来了。
Now again,
再说一次，
if you're doing your own MKAnnotationView subclass.
如果你自己实现MKAnnotationView的子类。
Doesn't draw a pin, it draws something else.
你不打算绘制一个大头针而是别的什么。
You could have your own callout,
你可以设计自己的标注，
you can put your own view up,
你可以把自己设计的视图放上去。
whatever you feel like you need to do.
你自己喜欢的。
But if you're using the pin-based one,
但是如果你用一个大头针，
this is the flexibility you have, is to do that left and
你就只能设置这些东西，左右两个
right callout accessory.
辅助视图。
Okay, that's what you're allowed to do.
这是你唯一能做的。
'Kay, so
in the demo, I'm going to show all of this ability here.
一会儿在demo里，我会给你们演示都能做什么。
So you create a MKMapView just by,
你能从故事板里直接拖一个
usually by dragging it out in storyboard of course.
MKMapView出来。
Just like you create, you know,
就跟你拖文字视图或者图片视图
a text view or an image view,
一样。
just drag it on out and size it to where you want.
拖进来然后设置大小。
But you can say MKMapView parenthesis, parenthesis and
你也可以通过 MKMapView() 来
initialize one.
初始化。
You can say MKMapView frame colon whatever cuz it's
你也可以写 MKMapView(frame:)，因为它就是一个UIView
a UIView.
而已。
One thing that's important about using MapKit,
要使用MapKit最重要的就是别忘了导入
you have to import MapKit.
MapKit。
Okay?
If you don't import MapKit, you're not gonna see any of
如果不导入，这些东西你就都
the symbols so don't forget that piece.
不能用，千万别忘了。
It'll be pretty obvious when you start typing,
你自己写代码的时候应该能挺容易就发现，
it's like woah, MKMap it won't escape complete.
因为你写MKMap的时候没有自动补全。
Well, it's because you didn't import MapKit.
这时你就知道是忘了导入。
The annotations that are on there,
地图上的注释点，
all the places where the pins are, that's just an array,
也就是那些大头针，实际上是一个数组。
okay, an array of MKAnnotation.
一个MKAnnotation的数组。
Now, I'm putting them in these slides as
在幻灯片里我写的是MKAnnotation
array of MKAnnotation.
的数组。
It's actually, as you might guess,
事实上，你可能已经猜到了，
an array of any object, okay, for historical reasons.
它是AnyObject的数组，因为各种历史原因。
But you cannot pass anything except for
但是你不能把MKAnnotation以外的东西
an MKAnnotation into these things.
存进这个数组。
So I've changed the code on my slides to just be
所以我在幻灯片里改成了MKAnnotation
array of MKAnnotation.
的数组。
Cuz that's what it is, it's an array of MKAnnotation.
因为它本来就是MKAnnotation的数组。
Okay?
Now notice that that's get only.
你注意到了这个属性是只读的。
So we'll talk about how you set
一会儿我们会讲如何设置注释点，
the annotations in a second, but that's how you get them.
但是在这你只能读取，
The protocol, as I talked about, coordinate, title, and
前边我说的协议，就是坐标，标题，
subtitle.
副标题那个东西。
Notice that the title and
注意看标题和副标题
subtitle are optional strings, okay.
都是可选的字符串。
But you really wanna set that title.
但是你必须得设置一个标题，
If you don't set the title,
如果不设，
pretty much everything's gonna be messed up.
就全乱套了。
So don't let that title be nil.
所以千万不要让标题为空。
Okay? The subtitle can be nil, but
副标题可以为空，但是标题
don't let the title be nil.
不可以。
And then CLLocationCoordinate2D you
CLLocationCoordinate2D，这个之前你们
know what that is from earlier slides,
已经看到过了，
that's just the latitude and longitude.
就是经纬度而已。
Okay, so
how do we add annotations since that thing is read-only?
既然注释点是只读的，那我们怎么添加呢？
Well, with methods like addAnnotation and
可以通过addAnnotation和addAnnotations方法，
addAnnotations, and removeAnnotation and
通过removeAnnotation和removeAnnotations
removeAnnotations.
删除。
Okay?
And the reason it does that that way is it just wants to
这样做的原因是系统就可以知道你加了
know when you add an annotation, so
新的注释点以便于它
it can update the map.
更新地图。
Okay.
Simple as that.
很简单。
It is generally a good idea, if you know what all your
如果设计时你就知道你所有的注释点，你最好提前就把它们
annotations are, to add them up front.
都添加了。
Okay? As opposed to kind of trying
这个好像跟用户现在在哪个位置，
to watch where the user is on the map, and
然后在地图上插一个大头针
add them as you go.
有点相悖。
Because you're gonna find that the map
这么做是因为地图视图跟表格视图一样
view is smart like table view, and it reuses those pins.
聪明，它们可以复用大头针。
Okay? So,
if you have a thousand annotations,
如果你有一千个注释点，
annotations are small, the views are big and
注释点很小，但是它的视图很大很耗能，
expensive, but map view is going to manage that for you.
但是地图视图会帮你管理它们。
Okay? So unless you
除非你在一个
have a ton of annotations in a very small space and somehow,
非常小的区域有非常多的注释点，
you filter them to show the user only some of them,
你应该过滤掉一些，给用户展示一部分，
you might as well put all your annotations in there.
不过也有可能你想把它们都展示给客户。
And let the map view be smart about showing which pins
地图视图会很聪明的知道在现在的地图上
are are visible at the, where the map is showing.
展示哪些大头针，
And then, as it scrolls around,
如果用户滚动地图，
it'll reuse the pins and be efficient about it.
它就会复用大头针以提高效率。
Okay?
When you have an annotation,
当你有一个注释点，
what does it look like on the map?
它在地图上是什么样的呢？
Well, that depends on the MKAnnotationView
这个取决于用来显示它的
that's displaying it.
MKAnnotationView
But again, the pins are usually how we do it, and
但是，通常我们都用大头针，
it looks like a pin.
You can set the color, it can be purple or blue or red,
你可以设置它的颜色，紫色蓝色或者红色，
I think.
And you can even set the image of that pin if you don't want
你甚至可以把大头针的图片换掉如果你不希望它看起来
it to look like a pin, but
像个大头针，但是你希望
you still want all the rest of behavior of the pin annotation
其他的特性都跟大头针注释点一样，
view like that callout.
比如标注视图。
Then you can change,
你可以换图片，
there's a property in there, you can change the image.
有一个属性，可以换图片。
When you touch on a pin, what happens?
如果你点击一个大头针会发生什么呢？
'Kay? Well one thing is,
首先就是，
if it's a pin annotation view, and as long as showing
如果这是一个大头针注释点，有一个canShowCallout属性让你确定
callouts is allowed, there's a can show callout property.
是不是允许弹出标注视图。
Then it's gonna put that callout up.
如果允许，标注视图就弹出来。
Okay?
So that's one thing that happens.
这是首先会发生的事儿。
The other thing that happens when you touch it is that
另外一个点击时会发生的事情就是调用
your map view's delegate
地图视图的代理方法。
gets sent the message didSelectAnnotationView.
didSelectAnnotationView
So you get told oh,
在这里系统就会知道
this person clicked on this annotation view.
有人点击了注释点视图，
And you can find out from the annotation view
你可以从这个方法的注释视图参数得知是哪个
which annotation that represents.
注释点被点击了。
Okay?
Remember that the callout is built
要记住标注视图在大头针生成的时候就已经
at the time that the pin is built, that view hierarchy.
通过视图继承关系生成了。
But you wouldn't want to do something expensive there,
所以在这个时候不要做非常消耗性能的事。
like for example, fetch that image,
比如抓取图片什么的，
that little picture of Venice there.
那个威尼斯的小图片。
I wouldn't want to fetch that from the network or
我希望这个图片只在注释点被点击的时候
something until it actually got clicked on.
才会开始从网络抓取。
Because that callout
因为如果没人点注释点的话，有可能
may never be shown if no one ever clicks on it.
标注视图永远都不会弹出来。
So, what a waste to fetch that image before then.
所以在那之前就抓取图片非常浪费。
Okay? But you're still gonna wanna
但是标注视图的左辅助视图
put the UIImageView as the left call out accessory.
依然是一个图片视图，
You're just not gonna put any
你只是在注释点被点击之前不
image in it till someone clicks on it.
加载图片而已。
So, how are these MKAnnotationViews created and
这些MKAnnotationViews是怎么加载而且跟你的注释点
associated with annotation?
数组联系起来的呢？
'Kay, it's very similar to table view, so this is a lot
跟表格视图非常类似，尤其是跟表格视图的
like table view's self or row in index path.
self或者indexPath的行很类似。
Okay, it's called viewForAnnotation, so it's
我们调用viewForAnnotation方法，
gonna give you an annotation and say create me a view.
它会在参数里给你提供一个注释点然后你需要为它建一个视图。
The first thing you're gonna try to do is dequeue
首先你需要尝试把一个复用的视图从队列
a reusable one.
取出。
So that's like you do in table view.
跟你在表格视图里做的一样。
And, but this time,
但是这次
if you can't find one, which is possible,
如果找不到，这是有可能的，
because there's no prototypes like there is in table view.
因为跟表格视图不同的是这里是没有原型的。
There's nothing in the storyboard that's
我们没有从故事板里加载一个
gonna make it create one.
进来。
So you have to check to see if view does equal nil,
所以你必须要检查视图是不是为空，
then you're gonna have to create a pin annotation view.
然后就要新建一个大头针视图。
But when you create it,
新建的时候，
there's two arguments to its initialize there.
它的初始化器有两个参数。
One is the annotation, but
第一个是注释点，第二个
another one is that reuse identifier.
是复用标识。
And that makes it so the next time you come around that pin
这样可以使这个视图在屏幕外的时候
might be reused if it went off screen.
可以被复用。
So this is how this works.
在没有原型的时候我们
There's no prototypes,
都是这么做的。
you have to kind of create the prototypes in code here if you
如果你不能从复用队列中取到一个的话，你就要用代码新建一个
can't get a dequeued reusable one.
原型。
And then you're usually gonna say whether
然后下面就需要设置是不是允许
you can show a callout.
弹出标识视图。
If you're using a pin annotation view,
如果你用的是大头针视图，
you're gonna say yes or no on the canShowCallout.
你需要设置canShowCallout的值。
And then, now you've got ahold of an MKAnnotationView.
这是你就持有了一个MKAnnotationView
You're going to get it ready to display,
下边要准备让它显示在屏幕上，
mostly by setting the annotation.
最重要的肯定是设置它的注释点。
Okay?
But also, you might set up those left and
你也有可能需要设置它标识视图的左右
right callout accessory views.
辅助视图。
So that's basically it, okay?
然后就差不多了。
And then you just return the MKAnnotationView.
然后就返回这个 MKAnnotationView。
So it looks a lot like self or row in index path.
非常类似于indexPath的行。
MKAnnotationView has some interesting properties.
MKAnnotationView有一些有趣的属性，
Like I said, you can set the image, that is the pin.
你可以给它设置图片，默认是个大头针。
You've got this left and
你也可以设置标识视图的
rightCalloutAccessoryView that you can set to an image view,
左右辅助视图，图片视图或者
button, whatever you want.
一个按钮，什么都行。
You can enable and disable it.
你可以激活或者隐藏它。
You can have a center offset, because with the pin, people
你还可以设置中心偏移量，因为人们一般习惯于点击
are gonna be clicking on the head of the pin, but the pin
大头针的头部，而大头针在地图上的点实际上是它的底部，
is actually pointed into the earth at a different spot.
跟头部并不是一个点，
So there's a little offset there.
是有一些偏移的。
And you can even have draggable pins.
你还可以设置可拖拽的大头针。
But if you have a draggable pin, then your MKAnnotations
但是如果你的大头针可以拖拽，那么你就需要实现注释点
need to also implement to the setter for coordinate.
坐标的setter方法。
Not just the getter for coordinate, but
不能只有getter，也需要
the setter as well.
setter。
Okay?
So, it's kind of a cool feature if one of the callout
有个很酷的特性就是如果你的标识视图的辅助视图，无论
accessory views, either the left or
左右，是一个UIControl，
right is a UI Control, like a UIButton usually.
通常是按钮。
Then, when it's touched, when the callout is touched, you'll
当它被点击的时候，地图视图的代理方法
get this mapView method, calloutAccessoryControlTapped.
calloutAccessoryControlTapped就会被调用。
So that's a really cool way to basically do target action
这是一个非常好的处理目标动作的方式。
like thing, when someone clicks on the callout.
就是当有人点击标识视图的时候，
Okay? Not on the pin, but
并不是大头针，
on the callout code.
They click on the pin first, the callout comes out.
如果先点击大头针，标识视图才会出来。
Now if you click on the callout,
现在如果你再点击标识视图，
if you put a UI control in there,
如果那上边有一个UIControl，
you'll get this message.
就会调用这个方法。
And then you can go do something, like segue.
在这个方法里你就可以做一些类似于跳转的操作。
Which is what we're gonna do in our demo.
一会儿我们的demo里就会这么做。
Okay, so, I said that in didSelectAnnotationView,
我前边说过在didSelectAnnotationView方法里，
which it gets called when the pin gets clicked on,
当大头针被点击的时候会调用，
this is where you might wanna load up an image.
你需要在这里加载图片。
So here's what an example of that might look like.
这里就是一个例子。
I'm here in didSelectAnnotationView.
我在didSelectAnnotationView方法里。
I'm saying, is the leftCalloutAccessoryView
我先检查标识视图的左辅助视图是否是
a UIImageView?
一个图片视图？
If it is, then I'm gonna set its image to something, and
如果是的话，我要设置它的图片，在这里
I might probably start a download in another thread
我可能要在另外一个线程开始下载。
here, okay?
In my demo of course, as you, as I'm famous for,
在我的demo里，你们应该知道，
I'm just gonna.
我肯定会先
Block the main thread and make a call, but you don't need to
阻塞住主线程，但是你不需要再看这种代码了，
see that code, you've done it yourself numerous times,
你自己肯定已经做过很多次这种
to go do a fetch.
抓取操作了。
Now, If you do a fetch in another thread,
如果你在另外的线程里下载图片，
when it comes back,
当它回调的时候，
make sure that this annotation view is still associated with
要确定这个注释点视图依然关联着这个注释点，
that annotation, because it gets reused.
因为它有可能被复用。
'Kay, everybody understand that?
大家都明白这个问题吗？
Raise your hand if you understand
如果明白我刚才说的复用的
what I'm talking about with this reuse.
问题的话就举手。
Okay?
How many people understood that in table views,
有多少人理解表格视图里
the cells got reused?
单元格的复用？
'Kay, 100% of the people.
好，所有人都明白。
So in a table view, if you went off and fetched an image,
在表格视图里，如果你去另外一个线程下载图片，
and it came back, isn't it possible that image would no
当他回调的时候，这个图片可能就不是加载在刚才的
longer be associated with that cell?
那个单元格里了。
Okay, everyone, raise your hand if you understand that?
如果能理解就举手。
Okay, everybody understands that.
好，大家都理解了。
Same thing here, okay?
这里也是一样的，
If you click on a map pin, and the callout comes up, and
如果你点了一个大头针，标识视图出来了，
you start a download for that little callout, and
然后你开始为标识视图下载图片，可能会用
then it takes a long time, and
很长的时间，
meanwhile they click on another pin and
这时你又点了另外一个大头针，然后地图
scroll us to another place on the map,
滚动到了另外一个位置，
that thing might be reused.
前边的那个大头针可能被复用了。
And now the image comes back, and
这时图片下载好了，
it's no longer applicable there.
那么图片显示在这就是错的了。
Okay?
So now we all understand, okay.
大家都明白了，对吧？
[LAUGH] I'm glad I went through that.
我很高兴我把这部分讲明白了。
All right.
The map view.
好了，继续讲地图视图。
How do you configure the map view's display with map type?
怎么配置地图的类型呢？
You just say whether it's satellite, a hybrid view, or
它是卫星视图，混合视图还是
the standard street view.
标准的街道视图呢？
You can show things like the user current location.
你可以展示用户当前位置。
If you say showUserCurrentLocation true,
如果你把showUserCurrentLocation设置为true，
then it's gonna put a little pin on there that always shows
就会有一个小个的大头针显示你当前的位置，
where you are, the user of the phone.
手机用户的位置。
Okay, which is kinda fun.
很挺有趣的。
And you can find out whether that's currently showing and
你可以设置当前位置是不是在地图上，以及
what the user's location is.
用户的位置信息。
The user's location comes back as an MKUserLocation, which
用户的位置信息返回类型是MKUserLocation，这是一个
is an MK annotation so it has coordinate and all that.
MKAnnotation，所以它有坐标和别的。
It's just for the user, so you know it's for the user.
这是给用户用的。
You can also restrict the interaction with the map.
你还可以限制地图的交互。
You might not want the person scrolling or
你可能不希望用户滚动地图或者
going out of a certain area.
离开一个特定的区域。
And you can control that by turning on and
你可以控制这些行为通过开关
off the scrolling and zooming.
滚动和缩放。
You can also turn off the pitching.
你还可以关掉拉伸手势。
The Apple maps is a 3D.
苹果的地图是3D的，
Kind of a pseudo 3D thing, right?
其实是一种伪3D。
Where you can tilt your camera up so
你可以把视角调高，这样就可以
that you're looking down.
往下看。
You can see the buildings.
可以看见建筑。
You've probably all seen that, so you can control whether
你可能以前见过，所以你可以控制是不是允许用户这样做，或者
that's allowed or whether it's gonna be a 2D map only.
只是显示一个2D的地图而已。
And same thing rotation, do you always want north up or
转动也是一样的，你可能希望北面一直是朝上的，或者
do you want to allow the user to turn north off to the side.
你允许用户调整方向。
For that 3D thing, that kind of pseudo 3D, you can control
在3D的地图里，其实就是伪3D，你可以控制
the camera which is like where the camera, how high it is,
视角的高度，
how steep it's looking, down that kind of stuff.
向下看的角度等等。
Using an MKMapCamera you can just specify
用MKMapCamera你可以调整
the coordinates of the camera.
视角的坐标。
And the altitude is eyeAltitude, okay,
高度就是眼睛的高度。
where it's looking from.
是从哪里往下看的。
So, that's kinda cool.
这个非常酷。
You can also control what part of the map is showing with
你还可以通过MKCoordinateRegion控制显示地图的哪个部分。
the MKCoordinateRegion.
So an MKCoordinateRegion is just a CLLocationCoordinate2D,
MKCoordinateRegion就是一个CLLocationCoordinate2D
that's a spot on the map.
地图上的一个点。
And then an MKCoordinateSpan which is latitude and
MKCoordinateSpan是围绕这个点的经纬度
longitude distance around that, okay?
距离。
And that's what it's gonna use to show the map.
这个就是我们需要显示在地图上的部分。
Of course the map has a certain aspect ratio which
当然我们还需要维护一个高宽比
it's going to maintain.
的值。
So it's gonna try and
设置好以后，它会按照这个值尽可能
show this region as best as possible,
的展示这个区域。
I think it shows the entire region, so
我认为它会展示整个区域。
there might be a little extra stuff depending on the aspect
可能会有一些多余的部分，这个取决于你屏幕或者
ration of your screen or the view, versus the aspect ratio
视图的高宽比对比你需要显示区域
that you're requesting in the region.
的高宽比。
You can also just set the center coordinate.
你也可以直接设置区域中心的坐标。
Like where do you want the center of the map is.
类似于你希望地图的中心的位置。
If you don't care if it's size,
如果你不关心地图的大小，
you just want to zoom it to a certain spot, you can do that.
你可以让地图缩放到展示一个特定的点。
It could be animated.
这个动作可以是动画形式的。
You can also show annotation.
你还可以展示注释点。
So you can say, make sure these five annotations are all
你可以让5个注释点都显示在屏幕上，
on screen and it'll figure out a region to collect them.
系统会定义一个区域包含他们。
So, pretty cool way to control all that.
非常酷。
There's lots of kind of functions and
这里还有很多方法和函数可以用来
methods to convert from various coordinate spaces,
转换不同的坐标空间，
like the map has a coordinate system, okay?
比如地图有一个坐标系统。
The world has a latitude and longitude coordinate system.
我们的地球也有一个经纬度的坐标系统。
The view has a, you know,
在视图边界的内部，也有
inside this bounds coordinate system.
坐标系统。
And those three things are different.
很明显这三个系统是完全不同的。
Obviously.
And so you can translate between those things.
你可以在他们三者之间转换。
You understand why the world, the map is different because
你们知道为什么地球和地图的坐标系统不同吗？
the map is a projection, right, of the earth.
地图是地球在平面上的投射，而地球
The earth is a big sphere.
是一个巨大的球体。
In case you didn't know it's round.
不是圆形的。
And so when you flatten it out into a flat screen it kind of,
所以当它被平铺在一个屏幕上的时候，它就会被
you know, bends out.
弯曲。
So you need to map that ,and so those,
所以需要建立它们的对应关系。
that's why the coordinate system's not exactly the same
这就是为什么我们说起视图内坐标系统的时候
as if you're talking about the view coordinate system.
会有不同的系统。
So go look through the documentation there's probably
如果你去看文档的话，会发现大概有25个函数以及
25 different functions, and probably another dozen or so
10几个函数
methods that will convert back and
用来来回转换这些
forth between all these things.
坐标系统。
Another map view delegate method
地图视图的另外一个非常有趣的
which is kind of interesting is didChangeRegionAnimated.
代理方法是didChangeRegionAnimated。
So, this is telling you that the region that it's showing
它会告诉你现在显示在地图里的区域变化了
in the map changed and I've finished animating it.
而且我已经完成了切换动画。
Now why do you want to know that?
为什么我们需要知道这个呢？
Well because sometimes you wanna
因为有些时候你需要
do what's called animation chaining in the map view.
调用地图视图的动画链。
So let's say you're looking at New York City, and
举个例子，如果你的地图现在显示的是纽约市，
you wanna switch the user over to looking at San Francisco.
你想切换到旧金山，
Well you could just say set region San Francisco.
你可以把当前区域设置成旧金山。
And it would [SOUND] zoom over there really fast.
这样地图就会呼的一下快速的平移过去。
So fast that you wouldn't see anything in between.
快的你根本看不清中间的东西。
You wouldn't see Kansas or anything on the way, okay?
比如你不会看见中间的堪萨斯。
But a better way to do it would be to zoom out to show
一个更好的办法就是先把地图放大，展示整个美国，
the whole United States and then zoom in to San Francisco.
然后再缩小到旧金山。
Right?
See how that would look better?
这样会更好一些对吧？
You're up in New York, up to the United States and
现在是纽约，放大到整个美国，在
down to San Francisco.
缩小到旧金山。
Well the way to do that is you set your region to be
这么做的方法就是把你的区域设置成整个美国，
the entire United States, and
然后动画完成的时候这个
when that animation finishes you'll get this.
方法就会调用。
And now you set your region to be San Francisco.
这时你把区域再设置成旧金山。
Simple chaining.
简单的动画链。
Okay?
明白了吧？
Searching for places in the world by name.
还可以用名字搜索世界上的地点。
So this is a really cool feature,
这个非常酷。
where you can actually look things up by name.
因为可以通过名字来找地方。
So you could, for example, have a query like,
你可以做一个查询，比如这样，
show me Ike's, which, I guess, is not gonna work any more.
我搜索 "Ike"，我估计应该找不到什么地方。
But you should say show me Ike's and
你可以用"Ike"建立一个
you create this query that has an n there and
查询然后再建立一个
then you create an MKLocalSearch.
MKLocalSearch
And you give it that request and
你把查询赋给它，然后它就会
it will fire off a thread to go out on the network,
在另外一个线程开始使用网络查询。
look up Ike's somewhere in some database, and
在数据库里查询 Ike，然后返回
return information about where it is to you, and
相关的信息，
it'll return to you on this other thread.
同样也会在另外一个线程返回给你。
I believe the, all right, I'm sorry, in this closure.
我相信，哦对不起，在闭包里返回给你。
And I believe this closure executes on the main queue,
我相信这个闭包是在主线程执行的，
because this is all UI stuff so that closure you don't have
因为我们这个框架都是关于UI的，所以这个闭包你不需要担心
to worry about it being on a different queue.
它是在另外一个线程执行的。
So it can execute this closure with the response it got and
这个闭包会返回查询结果然后
then you can put it on your map.
你就可以把它们放到地图上了。
It gives you an MKPlacemark, it actually gives you
它会返回一个MKPlacemark ，实际上是一个MKMapItem包含一个
an MKMapItem and inside that there's an MKPlacemark.
MKPlacemark
An MKPlacemark
MKPlacemark里面包含
gives you more than just the latitude and longitude.
经纬度，
It gives you the name of the location, Ike's, and
位置的名字，邮编
the postal code, the region it's in, and all that stuff.
它所在的区域等等，
So, it's kind of a super location thing.
就好像是一个超级的位置信息。
And, if you have a map item, and you're not showing maps in
如果你有一个 MKMapItem，但是在你的app里没有显示地图
your app, you can actually open it up in the maps app by
的功能，那么你可以通过调用 openInMapsWithLaunchOptions 方法
saying openInMapsWithLaunchOptions.
来在一个地图app里打开它。
And you give these various options like,
你可以传递很多的选项，比如
do you want to show traffic?
你是否希望现实交通，
Okay, this is a, some kind of driving thing, you want to
这是与驾驶有关的， 你可以显示交通或者别的什么，
show traffic or whatever, you put the options in there.
把你需要的选项传递过去就好了。
And the map item will display on the maps app, okay?
然后这个item就会显示在地图app里。
So that's local searching.
这个是位置搜索。
You can also get a similar thing for directions,
关于方向，也有一些类似的东西。
you wanna go from one place to another and
你希望从一个地方去到另外一个地方，
it will send you back some routes that you can get there.
它会返回给你路线。
One, two, three routes maybe, and
可能是一条两条三条路线，
it'll also even give you a drawing.
而且会画在地图上。
A thing called an MKPolyline
这种路线叫做MKPolyline。
which I'm gonna talk about in a second.
我一会儿会讲到这个。
That you can overlay onto the map to show the route.
你可以在地图上绘制路线了。
So that's kinda cool.
非常酷。
'Kay and this also asynchronous just like
这个跟刚才讲的位置搜索一样都是
the last local search was.
异步的。
Okay.
So let's talk about those overlays, like MKPolyline,
下面我们来讲覆盖层，比如MKPolyline，
that shows the root.
那个显示路线的东西。
How do you do overlays?
我们怎么去绘制覆盖层？
Overlays look very much like annotations.
覆盖层跟注释点很像。
In fact, the MKOverlay protocol is a subclass,
实际上，MKOverlay 是 MKAnnotation 的子类，
or sub protocol of the MKAnnotation.
或者说子协议。
So, an MKOverlay has everything MKAnotation has,
所以 MKAnnotation 有 MKAnotation 所有的元素，
coordinates.
比如坐标。
Which is the center of the overlay.
坐标就是覆盖层的中心。
And then the title and a subtitle.
然后就是标题和副标题。
And it also adds boundingMapRect.
还有boundingMapRect属性。
So that's the rectangle that contains this overlay.
这是包含整个覆盖层的矩形。
'Kay?
So, if you're driving from San Francisco to San Jose.
如果你开车从旧金山到圣何塞。
It contains that.
那这个矩形就应该包括它们。
It also has a method that you can ask it,
这里还有一个方法你可以知道是否与
do you intersect this other Rect.
传入矩形有交叉。
Now if you don't implement that method in your MKOverlay
如果你不在MKOverlay协议里实现这个方法，
protocol, it'll just use the boundingMapRect, and
那么它就只会用boundingMapRect，然后检查是不是
see if you intersect that.
跟这个矩形有交叉。
But you can actually have so if your,
但是如果你想要知道你的路线是不是
if you wanna see if the actual root intersects it,
经过某一区域，那么你就可以实现这个方法。
then you can actually see if it intersects, as opposed to
然后你就可以检查它是不是跟某个矩形有交叉，而不是去检查它是不是被
whether the rectangle contains it, which is kind of a gross
包含在某一个矩形里，那样只是很粗略的
estimate of whether it intersects.
估计。
So, just like with an annotation, you have view for
跟注释点一样，注释点可以自定义视图。
annotation.
You have the same thing, for overlays.
覆盖层也是一样的。
You can actually have view for overlay.
你也可以给覆盖层自定义视图。
But usually, what we do is use renderer for overlay.
但是通常我们都会重新渲染覆盖层。
So an MKOverlayRenderer,
这里就会用到 MKOverlayRenderer 。
is something that knows how to draw an overlay on the map.
它可以知道如何在地图上绘制覆盖层。
Okay?
And so usually you have to render for
通常我们需要返回一个渲染用来渲染
overlay and we're gonna return to renderer.
覆盖层。
Now we could write our own renderers.
我们可以实现自己的渲染，
It's just a sub-class of MKOverlayRenderer but
通过实现 MKOverlayRenderer 的子类，但是一般我们
usually we're gonna be using a overlay that's built in like
我们都会用系统自带的渲染，比如MKPolyLineRenderer
MKPolyLineRenderer which is for drawing that route along
是用来画路线的。
the roads or MKCircleRenderer which renders circles.
MKCircleRenderer 用来渲染圆形。
Or MKPolylineRenderer.
或者 MKPolylineRenderer
Which, PolygonRenderer, rather.
不对，是 PolygonRenderer
Which is going to render some polygon.
用来渲染多边形。
Arbitrary Bezier polygon.
用贝塞尔曲线绘制的任意多边形。
Or even the MKTileOverlayRenderer.
甚至是MKTileOverlayRenderer，
Which will render tiled images.
可以渲染平铺的图片。
And you can use the last one there to replace the Apple
你们可以用这个把苹果的地图替换成
maps with your own map.
自己的地图。
So people have done some pretty cool apps.
有人做了一些很酷的app。
We've had ancient maps, some ancient mariner maps.
他们做了一些古地图，古代的航海图。
You know and
你现在知道了
they would actually over, you know use the tower renderer to
他们实际上是用最后的这种方式渲染，从而达到用自己的地图代替苹果
put that in the place of Apple maps.
自带地图的目的。
So they're still getting all the same feature of the Apple
所以这些地图都有跟苹果地图完全一样的特性比如
maps where they can zoom around, set the region, but
缩放，设置区域，但是它们的背景
they're using these kind of cool ancient maps
用的是非常酷的古代地图。
as the the background.
And they showed things like people who sail around
这样他们的app就可以记录人们的路线，
the world and they showed their track but
但是这些路线确显示在古代的地图上，
overlayed on these ancient maps which is kinda cool.
非常酷对吧。
So you can do all of that.
这个就可以通过渲染实现。
So all of these things, circles,
所有这些圆形，线型，
polylines, polygons they have their own renderers.
多边形，它们都有自带的渲染。
You don't have to write your own renderer.
你不需要写自己的渲染。
You just have to create an MKPolyline which we're maybe
我们一会儿可能会在demo里就会建立一个
gonna do on the demo.
MKPolyline 渲染。
I don't think we'll have time for that but we might.
也许没时间做这个了不过也是有可能的。
And the, then you just use this as the renderer.
你只需要调用这些自带的渲染就可以了。
And that's it.
All right. So it's time for the demo.
好了，开始今天的demo。
So what I'm gonna do is I'm going to load up a GPX file.
今天我们要做的就是加载一个GPX文件。
I have a parser, a GPX parser,
我有一个GPX解析器。
that I've written that just parses the GPX file.
是我以前写的用来解析GPX文件的东西。
And really it just returns two things.
它实际上返回两个东西。
Waypoints, which are just, you know, latitude and
一个是路点，你懂得，就是经纬度，
longitude, with possibly some hyperlinks to images or
还有可能有图片的链接或者别的什么。
other things like that.
比如
Timestamp.
时间戳。
And then it also returns what are called Trax.
还会返回我们叫做 Trax 的东西。
And a track is just a bunch of fixes, a bunch of waypoints
实际上就是很多带有时间戳的路点。
with timestamps that show when you went on a trax.
用来显示我们运动的轨迹。
So that's it.
就是这些。
The overlays, if we had time for
覆盖层，如果有时间的话我们可能
if which I don't think we're going to.
会做一下，不过很可能没时间。
We might would be the trax.
我们会做一下trax。
And then these pins would be the waypoints,
地图上的大头针就是路点，
just these waypoints.
我们刚才说到的路点。
Okay?
So the waypoints inside the trax, we can't fix this.
在trax里的路点我们叫做 fix。
Just so we're not confused about the difference.
这样就不会有名称上的混淆。
So waypoint is a stand alone waypoint,
路点就指的是单独的路点。
that's gonna be a pin.
就是地图上的大头针。
The fixes are inside the track.
fix 就是trax内部的路点。
Okay?
And so, because I won't get back the slides, Friday,
今天我们不会再回到幻灯片了，周五会有
section, Apple Watch
Apple Watch的内容。
And then next week, all kinds of topics I'm gonna cover
下周，我会谈到包括持久性存储在内的幻灯片上的
next week including persistence,
话题。
which I didn't get to on Monday.
应该周一讲的但是没讲。
But on other things not even on this list I'll probably
不过在这里边没有的东西可能也会
ment, get into.
涉及。
All right.
So, we actually have Trax started so
我们前边已经开始做 Trax 了，
let's go back to Trax.
所以我们回来继续。
This was pretty much where we left off.
现在这里跟我们上次留下的差不多。
The only thing I changed about this is I renamed my view
唯一变的东西应该就是我把原来简单的 viewController 重命名成了
controller to be GPXviewcontroller instead of
GPXviewcontroller 。
just plain viewcontroller.
And I also put the GPX parser code in here,
我还把我写的GPX的解析器相关代码放了进来。
which I'm gonna show you in a second.
一会儿就给你们看。
Otherwise you can see we still have this app delegate.
这里你看到的是 app delegate。
We're posting this notification here.
我们在这里发布了一个通知。
And now here's my GPXController.swift.
这里是我们的 GPXController.swift 。
And I'm getting,
I took out the little text view that was in here.
我把之前加过的文本视图去掉了。
And so here I'm adding the observer and
在这里我加了一个观察者来监听
I'm getting notified.
这个通知。
So in here we are going to just have to take this URL,
这里我们可以取到一个URL。
it's a URL for a GPX file.
这是GPX文件的URL 。
So we're gonna use this GPX parser that I
这里我们要用到我之前说过的
was talking about.
GPX解析器。
To parse it, get the waypoints out of there.
来解析，得到路点的信息。
Then we're gonna put those waypoints on the map.
然后我们就可以把路点放到地图上了。
That's the first thing we're gonna do.
这是我们首先要做的事儿。
And if we have time, which we won't,
如果我们还有时间，不过应该是没有，
we're gonna get the trax out and make an overlay of that.
我们要把trax取出来，然后在地图上做一个覆盖层。
But let's focus on the waypoints.
现在，我们先来做路点。
So, how are we gonna do this?
我们要怎么做呢？
First of all, I'm actually take a timeout and
首先我们要先把路点放下，做一些
write my, do my user interface for this.
UI方面的工作。
Okay?
So let's go over to our storyboard, over here,
切换到我们的故事板。
and in my storyboard I've already changed this to be
在故事板里我已经把这个视图控制器从 ViewController 改成了
a GPX ViewController, instead of a view controller.
GPXViewController。
And I'm just gonna drag a map out, so I'm gonna go down here
我现在要拖出一个地图，找到下边的对象栏，
to my object palette here, I'm gonna search for map.
搜索地图。
There it is.
在这。
I'm gonna drag a map out and I'm just gonna put it in here.
把地图拖出来放在这。
Let's go ahead and put it in the right spot.
放到正确的位置上。
We'll put it right filling in the whole screen.
让它填满整个屏幕。
Let's do our constraints.
现在开始加约束。
Let's double check that our constraints look good.
再来复查一下约束是不是OK了。
Yeah. No magic numbers.
好的，没有魔法数字。
That all looks good to me.
看起来没什么问题了。
Let's create an outlet to it, so
然后建一个outlet。
I'm just gonna control drag into my controller here.
把地图 ctrl + 拖拽到我的视图控制器。
I'm gonna call this my mapView.
起名叫 mapView.
All right?
So now we're nice and hooked up to our user interface.
现在UI都正确的连接起来了。
And notice that we have an error here right away.
不过我们这里有一个错误。
That's because I have to.
那是因为我还没导入
Import MapKit.
MapKit。
Okay, if I don't import MapKit I don't get any of that
如果我不导入MapKit的话，我就不能得到这些字符。
symbology, the map, map, MapKit symbols.
地图相关的字符。
Okay? Now
when the mapView outlet gets set,
当我们地图视图的outlet连接好，
that's a good time to actually configure our mapView.
这是一个配置地图视图很好的时机。
And what do we need to configure that mapView?
我们要怎么配置呢？
Not much, I'm just gonna say that I want the map type.
没有太多东西，我只需要定义地图的类型为
To be the satellite.
卫星。
And I'm also going to set the map views delegate
然后把它的代理设置为self。
to be myself because as you saw in the slides
因为从幻灯片你们知道有很多东西需要
a lot of things we need to do with the map views delegate.
地图视图的代理去做。
So I have to say I'm an MKMapViewDelegate.
在这里加上 MKMapViewDelegate 。
Okay?
Let's make our screen bigger.
把屏幕弄大一点。
Okay.
What else we've got.
这又是什么错误。
Oh yes, all right.
哦，对了，
This is in the didSet of this.
配置应该在didSet里。
All right.
好了。
So as soon as that outlet is set, we're gonna make our
当我们的outlet连接好以后，地图就会被设置成
mapView satellite only, [INAUDIBLE] no roads over it.
卫星模式，看不到路名什么的。
And we're [INAUDIBLE].
然后我们［听不清］。
Now this is something probably we'd wanna
在地图模式这里我们后边可能会需要加一个
set with a segmented control maybe,
选择控制器。
because it has three options of some like that.
因为事实上应该有3个选项。
But here, I'm just gonna have the satellite only.
但是这里就设置成卫星。
Now, the next thing that I need is my public API,
下边我需要设置我的公共API。
basically, for my GPX viewcontroller, and I'm gonna have
对于我的GPX视图控制器来说，我的公共API就是
my public API be that you can set a GPX URL on me.
GPX文件的URL。
And if you set GPX URL, I'm gonna load it up and
如果这个URL设置了，我就要把它加载进来以显示
show you the waypoints and trax.
路点和路径。
Okay? That's basically the way
明白了吗？基本上就是这么
my thing works.
做的。
So what is this gonna look like?
那我要具体怎么做呢？
Well, let's do the didSet in here, so
我们在didSet这里做，每次
anytime someone sets the URL, we need to load it up.
有人设置这个URL的时候，我就要加载这个文件。
So I'm gonna say if the URL that they gave me is not nil,.
这里我要写如果给我的URL不为空。
Then I'm going to parse it, so I'm gonna use this new,
我就要解析它，这里我用到了新的GPX类，
this class, GPX, which I'll show you in a second.
一会儿我会给你们看这个类。
And it has a method called parse, and
它里面有一个parse方法，
you can see that parse takes a URL,
接受一个url的参数，和一个
and then a completion handler.
完成的回调。
Because parsing that GPX, it does need another thread.
因为解析GPX文件需要在另外一个进程进行。
Okay. And then when it's done,
当它完成解析的时候，
it calls the completion handler here.
这个回调就会执行。
So I'll pass the URL.
把我们的URL传进去。
And we'll do the completion handler.
现在写回调。
And I don't even need any of this.
参数这里我都不需要了。
I'll use dollar zero instead of this.
我要用$0来表示。
I haven't been doing that in the demos but
以前在demo里我没这么做过，不过在这
I'm going to do it here.
要这么写。
So dollar zero is the GPX so
$0是GPX类型的。
it creates an instance of this GPX class.
这个方法会创建一个GPX类的实例。
So let's go take a look at that GPX class over here.
现在我们来看一下GPX这个类。
Put it in Supporting Files, here it is.
应该在supporting files里，在这。
It's a simple class, GPX.
这是个很简单的类，GPS。
It has waypoints, an array of waypoints, an array of tracks.
它有一个路点的数组，轨迹的数组，
Routes are just like tracks,
路径跟轨迹很像，
but they're more like a driving route kind of thing.
不过路径更像是给开车的人用的。
So we're not gonna do anything with this.
这里我们不会用到。
So it's just waypoints and tracks.
只用到路点和轨迹。
We're gonna put these with pins, and
我们要把路点用大头针显示在地图上，把轨迹
we're gonna do this with overlays, time permitting.
用覆盖层显示在地图上，如果有时间的话。
Okay, and mostly it's just a parser.
总体来说这就是一个解析器。
It's an HTML parser, see,
HTML的解析器，看到了没？
it's parsing various HTML hoo-hahs here.
可以解析各种HTML。
Here's the track that it return, which you can see is
这里是返回的轨迹，你能看到实际上就是一个
basically just an array of waypoints, okay.
路点的数组。
Column fixes, but it's an array of waypoints.
名字叫fixes，实际上是路点的数组。
Here's a Waypoint.
这里就是路点。
Waypoint is just the latitude and longitude.
路点里有经纬度。
Also, it has info about that point,
还有关于这个点的信息。
just kind of interesting info.
就是一些有意思的信息。
It inherits from this class Entry,
它是从Entry类继承来的。
which is a basic entry which has the name.
这是一个含有名字属性的基本入口。
So the waypoints also have names as well.
所以路点也有名字。
And also, waypoints can have links.
另外，路点也可以包含链接。
So links are just, you know, URL references, basically.
链接就是URL的信息。
And you can get the URL, and
你可以得到URL以及
you can also get the type of thing it is.
URL内容的类型。
And so we're gonna use that to get thumbnails versus regular.
我们可以用它得到缩略图或者常规的图片。
All right, so back to our code here.
好了，回到我们的代码。
We've parsed this URL.
我们解析了这个URL。
And we've got the completion handler.
我们也有了这个回调。
By the way, I always like to user our nice Swift
这里我非常喜欢用swift语法里
closure as the last argument thing.
尾闭包。
So I'm parsing it, and
这里，我解析了，
I'm just gonna say, if I was able to successfully parse it.
如果解析成功。
So the thing that was passed to me, this $0.
这个GPX就会传递给我。这个$0。
Okay? And that was not nil, okay.
如果不为空。
Then I'm going to work on it.
我就要处理它。
And what am I gonna do to work on it?
我要怎么处理它呢？
Well, let's do the waypoints first.
我们现在处理路点。
I'm just gonna call a method handleWaypoints.
这里我会调用一个 handleWaypoints 方法。
So I'm gonna handle the GPX's waypoints.
用来处理GPX的路点。
Remember, that's just an array of that Waypoint class.
还记得他们就是路点的数组吧。
That's all it is.
就这样。
Also, by the way, when someone sets a new URL on me,
当然，如果有新的URL传进来，
I'm gonna clear all my existing waypoints off my map.
我要清理掉所有在地图上存在的路点。
Okay?
So I just need to implement these two methods,
我现在需要实现这两个方法。
clearWaypoints and handleWaypoints.
clearWaypoints 和 handleWaypoints。
What do I need to do that?
我要怎么做呢？
Let's do clearWaypoints first.
咱们先来实现 clearWaypoints。
Really easy, clearWaypoints.
非常容易。
I just need, this is private.
这个是私有的。
I'll try to do the privates today or remember to do that.
我今天试着把私有都注明。
So clearWaypoints, I'm just going to,
clearWaypoints，我只需要，
if my mapView has any annotations, because remember,
如果我的地图视图有注释点的话，你们应该记得，注释点这个属性是
annotations is the array of annotations.
注释点的数组。
If that's not nil, then I'm going to, oops, I typed then.
如果不为空，我就要，哦。我居然打了then。
[LAUGH] mapView.annotation.
mapView.annotation
Oh, sorry, remove annotations.
啊，不好意思，移除注释点。
I'm just gonna remove all the annotations in that case.
我这里要删掉所有的注释点。
mapView.annotations.
And here's an interesting thing,
这里有个有趣的东西，
okay, I want to remove those annotations.
我想要删除这些注释点。
And we've got a lot of any object going in here.
我这里得到的是很多的anyObject。
So I'm gonna make this annotations as MKAnnotation.
所以这里我需要类型转换成MKAnnotation。
Just so you remember that these annotations are always
所以要记住这里注释点的类型永远
arrays of MKAnnotation there.
都是MKAnnotation。
Okay?
So that's clearing them,
好，这里就是清除它们，
nothing necessary besides that to clear them.
除了清除啥也不用做。
How about handling them?
那么如何处理它们呢？
Well, this is gonna be pretty amazing.
好吧，处理的时候非常酷炫。
But handling them is almost just as easy.
但是也是非常简单的。
So handleWaypoints is going to be this array of waypoints,
参数就是路点的数组。
take an of waypoints.
So these waypoints are GPX.Waypoint.
类型是 GPX.Waypoint。
That's the type of thing that this GPX object returns.
这个是GPX解析器返回的类型。
And we are just going to say,
这里我们写
mapView.addAnnotations, the waypoints.
mapView.addAnnotations，那些路点。
And, we're also gonna say, mapView,
然后展示这些
show the annotations of these waypoints.
路点。
And do that in an animated fashion.
用动画的形式。
Now, this, you're gonna look at this and
你现在看见这个肯定会问，
say, can it be this simple?
就这么简单吗？
And in fact, it can be this simple.
事实上就是这么简单。
Let's make this is self.
在这加上self。
It can be this simple, as long as this is an MKAnnotation.
因为这是一个 MKAnnotation，所以简单。
Do you see?
看见没？
I'm passing to addAnnotations this array, so these things
我在addAnnotations方法里传入了这个数组，所以数组里的元素应该
better be MKAnnotations, which they are not.
是MKAnnotations，但事实上它们不是。
Because they just come from this GPX parser,
因为它们来自GPX解析器。
it doesn't know anything about MK.
解析器不会知道MK的东西。
It's a generic GPX parser, it doesn't,
它只是一个泛型的GPX解析器。
it's not a MapKit parser or anything, it's just generic.
它不是为MapKit或者其他什么东西做解析的，它只是泛型的解析器。
So we have to some how make this
所以我们需要给它实现
implement the MKAnnotation protocol.
MKAnnotation协议。
And we talked about how we can use an extension
我们之前讲过如何用扩展使得一个类
to make a class implement a protocol, and
遵守某个协议，这就是
that's exactly what we're gonna do.
我们现在要做的。
So I'm gonna create a new file here.
这里我们新建一个文件。
Okay?
I'm gonna call it MKGPX, cuz it's gonna have all the things
起名字叫MKGPX，因为我需要扩展所有的
I want to extend these GPX classes so
GXP类，让它们遵守协议，使它们可以
they work with MapKit, MK, all right.
与MapKit兼容。
So MKGPX, here it is.
建好了。
Instead of importing Foundation,
这里不再导入Foundation了。
I'm gonna import MapKit,
而是导入MapKit。
because these are all going to be things about MapKit.
因为我们要做的事儿都是跟MapKit相关的。
And so I'm just gonna have an extension of GPX.Waypoint,
这里我写一个GPX.Waypoint的扩展。
and that extension is going to implement
让这个扩展实现
MKAnnotation protocol.
MKAnnotation协议。
Okay? So this is what I was talking
这就是我以前讲过的
about before where you can do this.
如何去实现协议。
This really makes your code simple
这让你给一个对象实现协议的时候
to be able to make an object implement another protocol,
的代码非常易懂。
as long as you can do it without any storage,
因为这都是跟存储无关的事。
because of course, extensions can't have any storage.
当然，扩展也不能做存储相关的事儿。
But here we can easily do that.
后边就很容易了。
So, the three things, remember, are coordinate,
我们要实现3个属性，首先是坐标，
which is a CLLocationCoordinate2D.
也就是一个CLLocationCoordinate2D。
And title, which is a optional string, but
然后是标题，一个可选的字符串，
we never want that to be non-optional.
我们从来不想让它变成非可选的。
And subtitle, which is also an optional string.
副标题也是一个可选的字符串。
So these are the three things we have to implement
如果我们希望这个东西变成MKAnnotation，就要实现
if we want this thing to be an MKAnnotation.
这三个属性。
So let's do that, super simple.
咱们开始吧，超级简单。
Here we're just gonna return a CLLocationCoordinate2D,
这里我们会返回一个 CLLocationCoordinate2D
with the latitude being our latitude.
经度就是我们类里自己的经度。
Okay? This is just a property in
这只是类里的一个属性而已。
this, the latitude, and longitude being the longitude.
纬度就是用类里面的纬度。
Okay?
So I just created a new one of these.
我这里新建了一个对象，
This is just calling its initializer.
调用了它的初始化器。
And I just pass my own latitude and longitude,
传入了我自己的经纬度。
could not be any simpler.
非常简单。
The title is also just as simple.
标题也很简单。
I'm gonna return my own name.
我只需要返回我自己的name属性。
I showed you in the code there,
我刚才给你们看代码了。
that GPX.Waypoints, they know their name, okay?
GPX.Waypoints有名字的属性。
We call it title in MKAnnotation,
我们把它当做MKAnnotation里的标题。
they call it name.
在类里我们叫名字。
And similarly here, there's return info,
副标题也差不多，我们返回info。
which is just the information about this waypoint.
就是关于这个路点的信息。
Back here, in our GPXViewController,
现在回到我们的GPXViewController
we have to, when we get the URL,
当我们拿到URL的时候，
we forgot to set our model here to be
哦，我们忘了在这设置我们的模型了，
this URL here, that's all.
设置一下就好了。
Okay.
So here's Stanford, we'll drag, this,
这是斯坦福大学，我们拖到这，
this is just a GPX file with some, hello, there we go.
这就是一个GPX文件，哦，这里，
Accept. With some Stanford locations.
点接受，包含一些斯坦福大学的地点。
And you can see, they just put them on there as pins.
你可以看到，放置了一些大头针。
Okay?
And I can even click on them.
我能点击它们。
If I tap them, I get the callout, and it has the name.
如果我点击他们，标识视图就弹出来了，看到了名字。
Okay? Some of them even have
有一些大头针还有
a little info.
详细一点的信息。
Okay. Green Library,
Green Library,
get your study on.
信息是get your study on
Or here's Meyer.
这是Meyer
Meyer Library, rest in peace.
Meyer图书馆，在平静中安息。
>> [LAUGH].
>> So that's that one.
Let's drag a different one out,
我们拖另外一个文件进来。
let's get our vacation here.
我们开始度假了。
So this one's got a lot more stuff.
这个东西会多一些。
We see that.
看看这个。
We accept that one.
我们接受一下这个。
It clears out our old pins, loads up this new GPX file,
它清理了我们以前的大头针，加载了新的GPX文件。
and shows us a whole bunch of pins on here.
给我们加了一些新的大头针。
So let's see where the heck we are in the world.
看看到底是哪。
So I'm gonna zoom out.
缩小一点看看。
All right. Somewhere in the middle of
把它们居中。
nowhere here.
What the heck, where are we?
哦，这是哪。
Oh, we're not even in the United States,
我们貌似不在美国了，
we're in Canada somewhere.
好像是加拿大的什么地方。
Okay, so we're up there in Canada.
我们现在在加拿大。
All right,
I'm just pinching to zoom here right on the map app.
我缩放一下，
And we've got all these pins.
这样能看到所有的大头针了。
And these pins we can click on, and
我们可以点击这些大头针，
some of them have titles and subtitles.
有一些有标题和副标题。
But this is kind of cool.
很酷。
This looks like a pretty incredible country here in.
这好像是个很不错的地方
Canada and it's referring to things like,
look at this, views are spectacular even from here.
看这，还挺壮观的。
It'll be awfully cool if we could see those views with
要是我们能看到这些地方的照片就
some photos.
更酷了。
And so that's what we're going to do next.
这就是我们下边要做的事儿。
So, on these call outs, I'm going to add a left accessory
在这些弹出的标识视图里，我要加一个左辅助视图，
view, which is a UI image.
也就是一个图片视图。
Which is gonna have a thumbnail of the photo that is
给它加上在GPX文件里，某个路点自己的链接以
in the GPX file that's linked to this particular waypoint.
显示图片。
Notice that we're getting these pins and this callout,
注意我们现在能看到这些大头针和标识视图，
and I haven't implemented that method,
但是我还没实现mapView.viewForAnnotation方法，
mapView.viewForAnnotation, remember that?
记得吗？
So if you don't implement that method at all,
如果你不实现这个方法，
all you get is pins, red pins, and
那么你能用的就是大头针，红色的大头针和
all you get is a callout with the title and subtitle.
带有标题和副标题的标识视图。
That's all you get.
你只能得到这些默认的组件。
So if you want anything more,
如果你还需要更多东西，
like a thumbnail, you have to do that yourself.
比如缩略图，那么你就要自己实现。
So we're gonna do that ourselves by implementing that
我们现在要自己来实现这个方法。
method, so let's put that right down here.
现在开始。
And it's called mapView viewForAnnotation.
我写mapView的时候，你会看到
You can see that mapView has a lot, a lot,
有很多很多的
lot of delegate methods.
代理方法。
It can do an enormous amount of things here,
它们可以做各种事。
from the overlays, and all that stuff the animation
覆盖层，动画，
other things, the regions coming, going, all that.
区域，等等等等。
So we want, if we can find it here,
我们需要找到viewForAnnotation方法，
viewForAnnotation, there it is.
在这呢。
Okay, mapView, viewForAnnotation,
mapView，viewForAnnotation
here it is right here.
找到了，在这呢。
All we have to do is what we talked about in the slides.
现在我们要做的就是我刚才幻灯片里讲到的。
Frst of all, I'll say var view equals mapView.dequeue.
首先，我们写 var view = mapView.dequeue.
So I'm gonna dequeue.
这里需要重用。
Now, I need an identifier here?
我需要一个标识。
I actually think I have a bunch of constants.
啊，我之前应该写了很多常量。
Yeah, I did do that.
啊，在这呢。
Okay, so here's a bunch of constants,
这里是一些常量。
don't worry about most of them, we're not gonna get to
大多数我们都不需要去管，按照计划，
most of this stuff today, which is kind of planned.
今天我们只用到很少的一部分，
But I do have this annotation reuse identifier.
这里有注释点的重用标识。
So I'm gonna use that.
我要用它。
Constants dot annotation.
Constants.annotation
Hey, by the way, one thing I'm seeing some of you do.
哦，对了，这里顺便说一下，我看到你们有些人会那么做。
Constants, you all know that all types
在Swift里，所有的类型和常量都需要以
need to be capitalized in Swift.
大写开头。
Right?
So class is structs.
类啊，结构体什么的。
You should really capitalize constants as well.
常量也是需要大写的。
I'm seeing a lot of you do lowercase.
我看到你们有些人小写了。
It's kinda confusing to people when they see a lowercase they
人们如果见到小写会误认为这是属性，他们
think it's a property and they're wondering, oh,
就会好奇它是不是有setter和getter。
is this settable, gettable?
Or if you capitalize it, they're gonna say,
如果你首字母大写了，他们就明白
oh, all right, this is must be a constant or to type or
这可能是个常量或者类型什么的。
something.
So please, you know, capital letter for
所以，要注意，首字母大写
things that represent constants.
表示常量。
All right, so I get this view.
继续，我现在得到了这个视图。
Now if there's no de-queues-able,
如果不是重用得到的，
if you can't de-queue a annotation
如果不能重用，我就要
view then I have to create it myself.
自己建一个。
So if this view is nil, then I have to create it.
所以这里写，如果视图为空，我就要新建一个。
And I'm just gonna create it by saying MKPinAnnotationView.
这里写MKPinAnnotationView。
I'm gonna create one of those.
我要新建一个MKPinAnnotationView。
I'm gonna use this constructor, annotation.
我要用这个构造器，传入注释点。
The reuse identifier is the Constants.Annotation.
重用标识是Constants.Annotation
Since I'm using the same reuse identifier as here,
这里我用了同样的标识。
then in the future this view could get reused.
所以之后这个视图就可以被重用了。
I want this to show call out so
这里我需要它能弹出标识视图，
I'm gonna have canShowCallout equals true.
所以写canShowCallout = true。
Okay? It's good.
Now let's set the annotation equal to annotation.
现在我们设置它的注释点。
Now you might say, oh,
这里你可能会说，哦，
well look when I constructed this, I already did this.
在我新建这个视图的时候我就已经传入注释点了。
So that's true.
没错。
We could for example put this in an else, if you want that.
我们也可以把它写在else里，如果你想的话。
It's a little different than a slide.
这么写跟幻灯片有点不一样。
But if we dequeued we wanna make sure we set
但是我们重用的时候肯定希望可以正确的
the annotation to this annotation that was passed in.
传递注释点。
Because we're reusing this thing, okay?
因为我们需要重用。
So that's an important thing.
这个很重要。
Sometimes people forget this and they're like, hm,
有些人忘了设置，所以他们会
my annotations, when they get reused,
发现当他们的视图重用的时候，
they keep showing the old annotation.
它还在显示之前的注释点。
Well, now you know why.
现在你知道为什么会犯这种错误了。
And then we can just return this view.
到这里我们可以直接返回这个视图了。
So this code that we have right here
我们在这刚刚写的代码，实际上
is essentially what you get for free.
我们是可以不写的。
If you don't implement this method, this is what you get.
如果我们不实现这个方法，系统就会自动为你写这些代码。
Okay?
And actually, I'm gonna put something here.
所以实际上，我还需要加更多东西。
I'm gonna make it so
啊，我觉得
we don't have to do the airdrop all the time.
我们不必一直开着 airDrop。
Okay. In viewDidLoad,
好了，在viewDidLoad里。
I'm going to load up the URL.
我要加载URL。
I'm gonna say, gpxURL equals NSURL string.
这里我写 gxpURL = NSURL(String:)。
I'm gonna do http://www.stanford.edu/vacat-
http://www.stanford.edu/vacation.gpx.
ion.gpx.
So we'll just load it out of there.
我们在通知外直接加载它。
That way we can actually run it on here, so
我在这选一下模拟器，我们就能
that we can keep it all on screen.
一直让它在屏幕上了。
Okay, where was I?
我讲到哪了?
I was in here.
啊，讲到这了。
Okay, so now we basically got the same thing we had
还是原来的大头针。
with a pin.
So if we run this now.
如果我们现在运行一下，
And we get the exact same thing here, right?
我们得到了一样的东西。
We can still click, we've got the panorama.
点一下，我们看到了panorama。
So now we wanna add this little left call out.
我们需要给它左边加一个图片。
So we build this UI, this leftCalloutAccessoryView UI,
我们要构建这个左辅助视图的UI。
in this viewForAnnotation right here.
在viewForAnnotation方法里。
And it's very simple to do.
非常简单。
We're just gonna say.
只需要写。
First of all, we need to only do this for annotations that
首先，我们只需要给是路点类型的注释点加
are waypoints because we could have our map have a mix
图片，因为我们可能会有GPX里的其他类型。
of these GPX.Waypoints and other things.
So, I'm gonna say, if I can let waypoint
这里写，if let wayPoint =
equal this annotation, as a GPX.Waypoint.
annotation，是一个GPX.Waypoint。
Okay.
So if the annotation is a waypoint, then I'm gonna
如果注释点是一个路点，下边我就要
check and see if the waypoint has a thumbnailURL, we're
检查它是否包含一个缩略图的URL。
gonna have to implement that property in a second here.
我们一会儿要实现这个属性。
So if that's not nil, then I'm going to say that the views,
如果URL不为空，那么我的视图，
annotation leftCalloutAccessoryView
我的注释点的左辅助视图，
equals a UIImageView.
是一个图片视图。
And I'm actually going to give it a default frame which I
我要给它一个默认的大小，我这里正好
have a constant for.
有一个常量。
No matter what size of the image is,
不管尺寸多大，
I want the actual size of the imageView to be fixed.
我只是希望图片视图的大小是固定的。
And by the way,
如果
if this waypoint doesn't have a thumbnail, okay?
这个路点没有缩略图呢？
And in fact, also if it's not a GPX.Waypoint then I want
或者如果它根本不是一个GPX.Waypoint呢？那么我就希望
the leftCallOutAccessoryView to be nil.
它的左辅助视图为空。
So, again, you have to think about reuse.
我们还要考虑到重用。
Some waypoints are gonna have thumbnail URLs, some not.
有些路点有缩略图的URL有些没有。
If you wanna set this to nil, and then only set to an image
所以我们需要把它设为空，只有当有URL的时候，才
view, if it actually has a URL.
设置为一个图片视图。
So we have to implement this thumbnail URL.
现在我们来实现缩略图的URL。
That's pretty easy to do, as well.
这个特别简单。
We're gonna do that same little extension here,
我们在刚才那个实现协议的
where we put this.
扩展里做。
I'm going to have a little kinda helper function here
这里我要写一个辅助方法，叫做
which I'm gonna call getImageURLofType.
getImageURLofType
And it's gonna get a certain type.
参数是一个类型。
So, this type is gonna be thumbnail or large image or
类型可以是缩略图或者大图
whatever it comes subverted the type
或者别的什么。
thing to be thumbnails or images.
And here I'm just gonna go through the links
然后我遍历一下GPX.Waypoint里的
that are in this GPX.Waypoint.
链接。
So this is an array in GPX.Waypoint which is of these
这是GPX.Waypoint里一个链接的数组，我们之前
link thing we did.
看到过。
And if the link's type equals the type that I want,
如果链接的类型是我们想要的，
thumbnail or
缩略图或者
whatever, then I'm gonna return that link's URL.
别的什么，我就返回这个URL。
Okay? So
this a way that I can get the URL, so,
这就是得到URL的方法。
yes, so this needs to return NSURL.
啊，对，这里需要返回NSURL类型。
Okay?
And if I can't find it, then I'll return nil,
如果找不到，就返回空。
so then it doesn't have an imageURL.
也就是没有合适的URL。
So, to implement thumbnail URL, okay, which is the NSURL.
要实现缩略图URL属性 ，这是一个NSURL类型。
That's really easy.
这个非常容易。
We're just gonna return the get image of type thumbnail.
我们只需要返回getImageURLofType("thumbnail")
Okay? And we're also gonna have
还有一个图片URL的属性，
a var for imageURL, which is the actual image,
这是一个真正的图片，
not the thumbnail, but the actual image.
不是缩略图。
And now, we're gonna return getImageURL large image.
这里返回getImageURLofType("large")
Okay?
So people understanding what I'm doing here?
大家明白我是怎么做的了吗？
Okay, this links
is just something that's in a waypoint that tells you all
这些链接就是包含在路点里的一些
the HTTP links that are attached to this waypoint.
关于这个路点的HTTP链接
And I'm just looking through them to find either one
我遍历了它们找到我需要的类型，
that's type thumbnail or one that's type large.
缩略图或者大图。
Okay?
明白了吗？
So now this is working right here.
现在这里也没问题了。
So this is the left callout accessory.
这就是左辅助视图。
Now, I could actually load that image up right here.
我现在可以在这加载图片了。
I could set this accessory views image right here, but
在这加载辅助视图的图片，但是我们
we talked about.
讲过，
We don't wanna do that because right now,
我们不能怎么做因为在这个时候，
this callout has not been put onscreen.
标识视图还没有显示在屏幕上。
This is just the pin being created.
这里只是用来建立大头针的。
Okay, I'm creating this left callout exception review, but
这时标识视图还没有生成，所以
the actual callout is not being created,
我不能在这设置辅助视图。
not being shown, so I don't wanna go fetching things.
所以不能在这个时候抓取图片。
But I do actually, want that thing to be fetched, and so
但是我确实希望抓取图片，那么我就要
I'm gonna do that in another mapView delegate,
在didSelectAnnotationView这个
which is the didSelectAnnotationView.
代理方法里做。
Which is somewhere here.
在哪呢？
There it is, okay.
在这，好
So this is,
if the AnnotationView actually gets selected.
这个方法会在注释点被点击时调用。
So, now the callout is gonna go on there.
这个时候标识视图应该在屏幕上了。
And I wanna do that.
希望是。
So, what do I need to do in here?
那我现在做什么呢？
Well, again, I need to check and
还要再检查注释点
see if this annotation is a waypoint.
是不是一个路点。
So I'm gonna say,
这里写，
if the views.annotation is a GPX.Waypoint。
如果views.annotation是一个GPX.Waypoint。
Cause otherwise it's, there's nothing for me to do here.
如果不是，我就什么都不需要做了。
I'm also going to get that ImageView out of there.
我现在还需要取到图片视图，
So if the thumbnailImageView equals
所以这里写如果thumbnailImageView等于
the views.leftCalloutAccessory view, as a UIImageView.
视图的左辅助视图，类型是图片视图。
Okay? So
I was able to get that leftCalloutAccessoryView, and
我就拿到了左辅助视图，现在是一个
it turned out to be an ImageView, so that's good.
图片视图，非常好。
That should be a question mark.
这里应该是问号。
Okay?
So now I have the ImageView, so now,
我现在有了图片视图。
if I can let the imageData equal an NSData, okay,
然后写if let imageData = NSData
I'm gonna block main thread right here, contentsOfURL.
这里我要阻塞主线程了，contentsOfURL
And this is the waypoints thumbnailURL.
这里是waypoints.thumbnailURL
Okay?
This is blocks main thread!
阻塞了主线程。
Yikes, fix that someday.
一会儿再修复它。
If let image equals the UIImage with that data.
如果image等于这个data转换的UIImage。
So if I get all the way down here, then I can say that
到最下边，我可以写
the thumbnailImageViews.image equals that image.
thumbnailImageViews.image = image。
Okay?
All right, does every one understands all these
大家都明白这一大堆if let
if lets here, to get down there.
了吗？
And what do we have to initiate here with contentsURL
contentsURL这里出了
waypoint.thumbnailURL, oh, sorry.
什么错误？
[INAUDIBLE] Exclamation point, now I can unwrap this here,
感叹号，现在我可以解包这个可选值了。
because I wouldn't even be in this situation of having this
因为如果我没检查缩略图的URL是否存在，我就没
leftCalloutAccessory if I hadn't checked
必要去建立这个左辅助视图了。
the thumbnailURL here.
Okay?
All right, so, let's give it a go here.
咱们来跑一下，
Now, let's run this.
运行一下看看。
>> [COUGH]. >> See if this is working.
看看能不能行。
There's our pins here, so let's try this,
这是我们的大头针，试着点一下，
and sure enough, now we have this little Image View for
现在我们可以看见那个小的
all of these things.
图片视图了。
Now, this in some ways, has kind of made us
因为可以看见图片，这让我们在某种程度上感到
happy because we can see this image, but in some ways,
满意，但是从另一个方面来讲，可能体验会更差，
it's made it worse because we got these cool images here,
因为我们在这看见了这些非常酷的图片，这让我们更
and we'd really love to see them bigger, right?
希望看见大图。
So, what we really wanna be able to do is
所以我们现在特别想做的事儿就是可以点击
click on this Callout View and
标识视图，然后跳转到一个
segue to an Image View that's gonna show us these images
图片视图去展示这些图片的放大版。
much larger, so we can scroll around and zoom in on them.
这样我们就可以拖动缩放大图了。
We're going to put a little button right here, okay.
我们希望在这放置一个小按钮。
It's gonna be a detail disclosure button.
一个显示详细信息的按钮。
And we're gonna use that map view delegate method that
当我们点击一个带有按钮的标识视图的时候，一个地图视图的
gets called when you tap on a Callout that has a button in
代理方法就会被调用，
there, and it's going to segue, so let's do that.
然后做一个跳转，我们现在做这个。
First we gotta add that little button, so we do that the same
首先我们要先加一个按钮，就写在我们刚才
place up here where we did the leftCalloutAccessory.
初始化左辅助视图的地方。
We're gonna
这里先写
do rightCalloutAccessoryView equals nil.
右辅助视图为空。
And if we can let, oh, sorry, we can do,
然后if let，对不起
we'll use that if twice so let's put it up there.
我们要用这个if两次所以先放在这。
So here we're also gonna say if the waypoints.imageURL
如果 waypoints.imageURL不为空，
is not nil then we will let the rightCalloutAccessoryView
那么我们就把右辅助视图设置为
equal UIButton.buttonWithType,
UIButton.buttonWithType
UIButtonType.DetailDisclosure.
按钮类型是UIButtonType.DetailDisclosure。
And you're not gonna believe this,
你可能不相信，
but you're gonna have to say here, as UIButton.
但是这里需要写as UIButton。
And that's because inexplicably,
由于很难理解的原因，
this method returns any object, okay?
这个方法会返回anyObject。
Don't ask me how that got in there.
不要问我为什么，
But UIButton.buttonWithType returns any object.
UIButton.buttonWithType 确实返回 anyObject。
So we have to cast it to a UIButton.
我们需要转换成 UIButton。
Otherwise, it won't even look like it's a UIView so,
不然的话，它可能看起来就不像是一个视图。
it's kinda bad but, there you go.
这个比较奇怪，但是没办法。
And so now,
let's do that method I was talking about before.
现在咱们来实现我们前边说过的代理方法，
The mapView method or the callout is called,
辅助视图点击就会触发的方法。
that is right here, the very top one.
在这，找到了，最上面。
CalloutAccessoryControlTapped.
CalloutAccessoryControlTapped
Okay, so this gets called whenever that callout gets
这个方法会在标识视图被点击
tapped on with that thing in there.
的时候调用。
And inside here, we need to essentially segue.
在这个方法里，我们需要跳转。
Right?
And so how are we gonna segue?
要怎么做这个跳转呢？
Really, I should be checking here to make sure this is
我们需要在这检查跳转到的我们
really the one we want.
需要的地方。
But I'm just, in the interest of time,
由于我们只有三分钟了，
since we have three minutes left.
我们就直接写吧。
I'm just gonna show you how we would do the segue.
直接给你们看我是怎么写这个跳转的。
And we just say, performSegueWithIdentifier.
我调用performSegueWithIdentifier方法。
And we haven't talked too much about seguing from code.
我们之前没怎么说过如何用代码做跳转。
Some of you
did it in the extra credits of the assignments.
我看到你们有些人在作业里这么写。
And you might be doing it in your final project.
你们可能需要在期末项目里用到这个。
Which you just say, performSegueWithIdentifier.
只需要调用performSegueWithIdentifier 。
And you need to have the identifier that's gonna show
这里需要一个跟你故事板里匹配
up in the storyboard, which I'm gonna call ShowImage.
的标识，这里我有一个常量ShowImage。
And the sender here can be anything you want.
发送者传什么都行。
But you really want it to kind of be the thing that is
但是你需要传一个可以让跳转
causing this segue to happen.
正确发生的对象。
Which here really the AnnotationView.
在这里应该是注释点视图。
So I'm gonna pass this AnnotationView,
所以我这里传进来注释点视图。
right here as the sender.
作为发送者。
Now, that's great.
很好。
Do that segue by name, but
通过名字来跳转，
where does the segue actually get created?
但是我们这个跳转是在哪建立的呢？
What's the source and destination?
源头和目标是什么呢？
And that, we still do in our storyboard.
我们依然会在故事板里建。
So if I go here to my storyboard.
打开故事板。
I still create the segue by Ctrl+dragging.
我还是用ctrl + 拖拽来建立跳转。
Okay?
So let's get imageView.
我们需要一个图片视图。
I'm gonna steal it from Cassini.
我要从Cassini里偷一个。
Let's go back over to Cassini here.
咱们回来找 Cassini 。
We'll go, open up Cassini.
在这，打开 Cassini。
Let's grab its ImageView first,
让我们先把图片视图拷贝过来。
it's imageViewController.
这是图片视图控制器。
All right.
Let's get this showing its navigator too.
打开文件导航。
All right, so I'm gonna grab the ImageViewController and
我现在把图片视图控制器拖
bring that in.
过来。
It's kind of a supporting file.
放到我们的supporting file里。
Copy that in.
拷贝进来。
I'm also gonna open up Cassini storyboard and
我还需要打开 Cassini的故事板找到
find everything, here it is.
它，在这呢。
I'm gonna take this UIViewController, right here.
我需要这个视图控制器。
And I'm actually going to copy and
我现在要把它复制粘贴到
paste it into my storyboard.
我的故事板里。
Where is my storyboard?
我的故事板呢？
I threw a board down here.
记得在这。
Okay?
So I go in here and paste it.
粘贴进来。
Let's see if we can find it.
缩小一下看能不能找到。
There it is, okay?
在这，找到了。
Now remember, copying and pasting between storyboard is
在不同的故事板之前复制粘贴完全没问题，
works because it's all done by name,
因为它们都是通过名字记录的。
the names of the classes, the names of the outlets,
类的名字，outlet的名字。
the name of all that stuff.
所有东西的名字。
So that will all work fine here.
所以粘贴过来也可以正常工作。
So now we just need to create the segue from this
现在我只需要建一个从这里到
ViewController to this one.
这里的跳转。
And we're executing it in code, so we don't have to
然后通过代码触发跳转，所以我们就不必从一个
Ctrl+drag from a button or something like that.
按钮或者别的什么东西开始拖，
We're gonna actually Ctrl+drag
我们只需要从视图控制器这里
from the ViewController itself.
拖拽就可以了。
So, I'm gonna Ctrl+drag from this button, right here,
在这个按钮这ctrl + 拖拽，
to this ViewController, and create a segue, okay?
到这个视图控制器，建立一个跳转。
It's a show segue.
类型是show。
I'm gonna inspect it,
在检视器里找到它，
and set its Identifier here to be Show Image.
把标识设成Show Image。
Which is the thing that I used over here in my code.
就是我刚才在代码里用到的标志。
Right? That's my Constant here,
是我的一个常量。
Show Image.
Show Image
So that's how you do a segue from code.
这样就实现了用代码跳转。
And there was no way for us to do it any other way, because
事实上我们也没有别的办法，因为
the little callouts aren't there in the storyboard, so
标识视图不在我们的故事板里，我们不能
I can't Ctrl+drag from them.
从它们开始ctrl +  拖拽。
So I have to drag from the whole View Controller, and
所以我只能从整个视图控制器开始拖，
then I use this perform segue with identifier
然后我调用 performSegueWithIdentifier 这个方法
to cause it to be fired off.
触发跳转。
Now this is a normal segue.
这只是正常的跳转，
We still have prepareForSegue.
我们依然需要实现 prepareForSegue。
Okay?
We still have to prepare for this segue.
我们依然需要准备这个跳转。
And so I'm gonna do that.
我准备实现这个方法。
I'm gonna say if the segue's identifier equals
先要写，如果跳转的标识等于
Constants.ShowImageSegue.
Constants.ShowImageSegue
Then if we can get a waypoint out of that view's annotation
现在就要判断注释点是不是一个路点，
so this watch this okay.
注意看这里。
Sender as MKAnnotationView.
So first, we've gotta see if this sender, right here,
首先我们要检查这个发送者是不是一个
is the MKAnnotationView, which it should be.
MKAnnotationView，它应该是。
If it is, question mark, annotation as a GPX.Waypoint.
如果它是，加问号，as GPX.Waypoint。
Okay? So we can do all that.
可以一起做检查。
Then we've got the waypoint.
这里我们就得到了路点。
So here you can see how this optional chaining.
看到这些可选值是如何链接到一起的了吗？
Starts with something you've got to be, learned to do.
你应该开始学着这么去做，
Otherwise, you have so
要不然你就会写
many if, lets all the time it's ridiculous.
很多很多的if let，这样代码就比较丑。
So you gotta be able to do this kind of thing.
你们应该学着这么写。
And so
waypoint here won't be nil if all that makes it through.
这里路点不为空，后边我们就一直往下写。
So I'm gonna then, if I can let my ivc equal
if let ivc等于跳转的目标，
Segue.destination as an ImageViewController.
它应该是一个图片视图控制器。
Okay?
Then, I'm going to just prepare it.
那我们就准备它。
So I'm gonna set its ivc.imageURL equal to
把它的imageURL设置成
the waypoints.imageURL.
路点的imageURL 。
And I'm also gonna set the image's title to be
还要把图片的标题设置成
the waypoint's title name.
路点的标题，名字。
[SOUND] Okay?
So this is just normal prepare for
就是很正常的跳转准备，
segue here, nothing special.
没有特殊的东西。
Everyone understand that?
大家都明白了吗？
And the last thing I'm gonna do in the storyboard
租后，我要在故事板里
here is I'm gonna put all of this stuff
把这些东西都放到
in a Navigation Controller.
导航控制器里。
So, I'm gonna embed in Navigation Controller.
把它们嵌入导航控制器。
All right, so this is what our storyboard looks like,
好了，现在我们的故事板就是这个样子的。
right here.
在这。
Okay?
So, now when we click on those little Callouts,
现在如果我们点击标识视图，
it's going to do this segue, and
就应该触发这个跳转，
cause Image View to come up with the waypoint's image.
图片视图就会弹出来显示路点的图片。
So, let's take a look at that.
咱们来试试。
All right, here we go.
运行一下。
So, let's go find a nice interesting image here.
现在找一张图片。
Maybe this guy, right here.
这个吧，就这个。
Okay, nice tracks.
nice tracks
So, I'm just gonna click on here.
我点这里，
You actually don't even have to click right on here.
实际上不用点这个按钮，
I think if you click anywhere in the Callout,
点标识视图哪里都可以。
it tends to work.
就应该可以跳转。
And you can see that it has segue,
看到了吗？它跳转了。
not your Image Views are much nicer than mine.
你自己的图片视图应该比我的好看。
Okay, you get rid of the white space and all that stuff.
我这里白边太多了。
But it looks like that.
大概就是这样。
We could go, let's go out to this one or
我们再找一个，
maybe, what's a better one?
这个怎么样？
How about, I think this is a good one.
我觉得这个应该不错。
Yeah.
So this trip was a helicopter skiing trip.
直升机滑雪旅行。
There's the helicopter coming in.
看到直升机了。
So that's it.
就是这样。
Does everyone make sense there, what's going on?
大家都理解这些内容了吗？
All right, that's it for Maps.
好，以上就是关于地图的内容。
See you next week.
下周见。
>> For more, please visit us at stanford.edu
更多信息请访问 stanford.edu